<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        Geek About Town - Full Posts    </title>
        <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2020-05-07T09:20:40Z</updated>

    <id>/blog/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">@colin_loves_mat - a retrospective</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/colin-loves-mat-a-retrospective"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/colin-loves-mat-a-retrospective</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;An&amp;nbsp;Explanatory&amp;nbsp;Note&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s this scene in one of the &lt;em&gt;Wayne&amp;#8217;s World&lt;/em&gt; movies where after somehow screwing things up for Cassandra&amp;#8217;s band, Wayne and his team of misfits hijack a satellite signal to take over the airwaves specifically to beam a Crucial Taunt performance into the limousine of a specific record exec. This is kind of that. In sum, for anybody who isn&amp;#8217;t Mat Marquis (@wilto), for a period of several years I ran a Twitter parody account called @colin_loves_mat that riffed on @wilto&amp;#8217;s apparent loathing of The Decemberists. He never found out who I was, and so here I am, drawing&amp;nbsp;back&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;curtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hi&amp;nbsp;mat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;have you adequately prepared yourself? because&lt;br /&gt;
i will now remove the mask&lt;br /&gt;
of weird hipster affectations&lt;br /&gt;
that I donned as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/colin_loves_mat&#34;&gt;@colin_loves_mat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you will clearly observe from this website that I, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jnicholasgeist&#34;&gt;@jnicholasgeist&lt;/a&gt;, have &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ABSOLUTELY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; weird hipster affectations&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hi. I&amp;#8217;m Josh. I&amp;#8217;m more or less a random internet oddjob who, for a period of a few years, badgered you with maritime nonsense for my own (and hopefully&amp;nbsp;your)&amp;nbsp;amusement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You probably don&amp;#8217;t know me, but you might have seen some of my work.  Back in 2011-2012, I was doing a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/&#34;&gt;weird web stuff for the video game magazine &lt;em&gt;Kill Screen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including some stuff you may have seen. One of my favorite projects that I did for &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, my &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/infinity-blade/&#34;&gt;review of &lt;em&gt;Infinity Blade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, generated &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=http%3A%2F%2Fkillscreendaily.com%2Farticles%2Freviews%2Finfinity-blade&#34;&gt;some buzz&lt;/a&gt; of the &amp;#8220;hey look at this cool javascript thingy&amp;#8221; variety. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/savetherobot&#34;&gt;Chris Dahlen&lt;/a&gt; was Editor-in-Chief of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; at the time, and Chris had previously worked with Ethan Marcotte. Chris showed it to Ethan, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/beep/status/81543719127490560&#34;&gt;who seems to have thought it was cool&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was doing a lot more web stuff at the time than I am now (as is evidenced by the pronounced 2012iness of this website), and I followed you among other prominent web-carers-about on Twitter. I thought you were funny, and I was especially engaged by your enthusiastic disdain for the Decemberists (who, for the record, I love genuinely and unapologetically). But man, Mat, lemme tell ya the Decemberists aesthetic is an absolute delight to make fun of, so I did. For several years.&amp;nbsp;Versus&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think early on, I did try to mimic certain elements of @beep&amp;#8217;s tweetvoice to throw you off the trail, but looking back, I&amp;#8217;m actually both baffled and delighted that you didn&amp;#8217;t figure out it was me&amp;#8212;not because you had any particular reason to know who I was, but because literally the day before I created @colin_loves_mat this&amp;nbsp;conversation&amp;nbsp;happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jnicholasgeist?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@jnicholasgeist&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;Drowning&amp;nbsp;please.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mat Marquis (@wilto) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wilto/status/250622971444617217?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 25, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you didn&amp;#8217;t, so I just&amp;#8230; kept pestering you. I was aware of the parasocial nature of the interactions, but it seemed like we were both having fun, so I didn&amp;#8217;t worry about it too much&amp;#8212;until eventually,&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;und&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/colin_loves_mat?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;@colin_loves_mat&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;why&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Mat Marquis (@wilto) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wilto/status/700486669783453698?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;February 19, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My inference from that&amp;#8212;which may have been way overblown&amp;#8212;was that you had stopped seeing this as fun, and had started seeing it as invasive, and that was never something I wanted. I just wanted to make fun of the Decemberists, Mat. That&amp;#8217;s all I ever wanted to do. (In a way, it&amp;#8217;s all &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt; wants to do, isn&amp;#8217;t it?) I figured if you weren&amp;#8217;t having fun anymore, it was time&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so I did! And then forgot about it for four years, remembered last week, and here we are. You&amp;#8217;re up&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I hope you had some fun, and weren&amp;#8217;t too&amp;nbsp;creeped&amp;nbsp;out. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because mat&lt;br /&gt;
i only like to creep people out&lt;br /&gt;
with haunting minor-key melodies&lt;br /&gt;
about the ghosts of working-class Victorians.&lt;br /&gt;
and you are not one of those,&lt;br /&gt;
mat,&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;are&amp;nbsp;you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Now You're Thinking With Labels!</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/now-youre-thinking-with-labels"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/now-youre-thinking-with-labels</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re thinking based on the title that this is an in-depth labelmaker shootout&amp;#8212;well, that probably just means you know me pretty well. It&amp;#8217;s not, but that&amp;#8217;s well within the scope of the stuff in which I&amp;nbsp;am&amp;nbsp;interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, this is a reflection I stumbled into in response to a student asking for advice on an assignment.&amp;nbsp;He&amp;nbsp;asked,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know we are suppose to write about a group or culture that we belong to, but I honestly can not think of one that I consider myself to be apart of? I understand that such a statement may sound ludicrous, but as an individual I stray away from putting &amp;#8220;labels&amp;#8221; on others and in order to do that I must apply the same logic to myself. Is there any advice to help me come up with at least one group to write about? Am I thinking to deeply on&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;assignment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response fairly quickly got way too baroque, but in the process I ended up saying something that I think might be meaningful about pedagogy, [D|d]iscourse, rhetoric, and Too Many Zooz. Here are my afternoon&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;unexpurgated&amp;nbsp;ramblings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi,&amp;nbsp;_____-&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think that you&amp;#8217;re thinking too deeply about the assignment, but I think you might not be thinking quite deeply enough about labels. I don&amp;#8217;t know you personally, yet, beyond our somewhat spare interactions in these first couple of weeks of class, so I&amp;#8217;m going to try not to make any assumptions here. But I do want to set you thinking in a way that will hopefully help you find a way into a topic for this Writing Project. I am, almost certainly, going to way overboard with my answer, because you&amp;#8217;ve asked me the kind of question that is a) essential to the rhetorical journey we&amp;#8217;re taking in this class, and b) super fascinating to me as a person and thinker. (If you&amp;#8217;ll forgive me for labeling myself twice in&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;row.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its best, I think what we mean when we say &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t want to put labels on people&amp;#8221; is that we want to view each person as an individual, rather than as a stereotype, and that any labels we might apply carry with them implications that may not fit any given individual. I think that&amp;#8217;s a fine impulse, but I also think it misses something essential: &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;being an individual, by its very nature, puts us into communities. Communities mean commonalities&amp;#8212;things we share with some people that we don&amp;#8217;t share with others. Labels of one form or another are, in most cases, a necessary consequence&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance: do you like music? If there is any music that you like, you&amp;#8217;re relying on a label. You&amp;#8217;re saying that there are some sounds that you consider music, and some sounds that you don&amp;#8217;t. If you don&amp;#8217;t like all music equally, then there are also some kinds of music that you like and some that you don&amp;#8217;t. And maybe you do like all music equally. Maybe it&amp;#8217;s even important to you that you like all music, because you don&amp;#8217;t like labels. Maybe you just like what you like. That&amp;#8217;s awesome&amp;#8212;I&amp;#8217;m not going to tell you what&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I will tell you, though, is that without labels, there can be no difference. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CvFH_6DNRCY&#34;&gt;Debussy&lt;/a&gt;. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-ywQW_4UaI4&#34;&gt;The Knife&lt;/a&gt;. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o8YHVQGfFLs&#34;&gt;Wingnut Dishwasher&amp;#8217;s Union&lt;/a&gt;. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jMe6Y8GDVEI&#34;&gt;Too Many Zooz&lt;/a&gt;, a lot. I can say that it&amp;#8217;s all music&amp;#8212;which, again, is still labeling it&amp;#8212;but without applying some sort of label, I can&amp;#8217;t say that there is any difference between those groups whatsoever. (Notice: the names of the artists are,&amp;nbsp;themselves,&amp;nbsp;labels.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you watch that Too Many Zooz video&amp;#8212;go ahead, I&amp;#8217;ll wait, it&amp;#8217;s amazing and everyone should have the right to experience it&amp;#8212;you will almost certainly be knocked on your butt by the unfathomable talent of Leo Pellegrino, far and away the most prodigious baritone sax player I have ever seen in my life. He&amp;#8217;s an incredible musician, and he plays an instrument that&amp;#8212;at least in my own estimation&amp;#8212;very few people feel it worthwhile to become incredible at. &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/jMe6Y8GDVEI?t=380&#34;&gt;I mean like seriously wtf.&lt;/a&gt; I can&amp;#8217;t call him a musician without labeling him, or a baritone saxophonist, or a prodigy. If I make space in my ontology for the existence as such a thing as a baritone sax&amp;#8212;labeling some configurations of brass (a label) in such a way that excludes others&amp;#8212;I also recognize that some people play the baritone sax and others don&amp;#8217;t (label), and if I begrudgingly accept that is true, then I&amp;#8217;m admitting the existence of&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;commonality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;#8217;t make all baritone sax players the same. It doesn&amp;#8217;t reduce them to a stereotype. In fact, I have to create the label in order to acknowledge Pellegrino&amp;#8217;s individuality. I have to say that he is this kind of thing in order to acknowledge that he is so unspeakably good at being that kind of thing. And I think this is the rhetorical essence and necessity of labels. If I decide that I want to address an audience of young people, I&amp;#8217;m labeling them, and I&amp;#8217;m also almost certainly going to make assumptions about members of that community that are not true in all cases. &lt;strong&gt;But&lt;/strong&gt; the essence of that label is the recognition that &amp;#8220;young people&amp;#8221; probably have some things in common that they perhaps do not share with people who are&amp;nbsp;not&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;young.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more thing about Too Many Zooz. If you ask them what kind of music they play, they will tell you that they play &amp;#8220;Brasshouse.&amp;#8221; As far as I know, there is no other band on the planet that identifies as &amp;#8220;brasshouse,&amp;#8221; although it wouldn&amp;#8217;t surprise me if others have come to emulate them. &amp;#8220;Brasshouse&amp;#8221; is a label that they built themselves to describe what they do. It is by labeling themselves that they make themselves individual, different from others. &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;We are not ska, not big band, not Tower of Power, not swing, not any of the other labels that apply to horn-heavy music. We are brasshouse. By labeling themselves, they reify themselves as themselves-&lt;em&gt;qua&lt;/em&gt;-themselves.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of which is to say, when I am asking you to identify a group or culture that you belong to, I am not asking you to define yourself explicitly by a label, with whatever undue stereotypes or constraints you think apply to it. Rather, I&amp;#8217;m asking you to identify something about yourself which you share in common with some people&amp;#8212;some community&amp;#8212;but not others. I&amp;#8217;m not asking for the old stand-up staples of &amp;#8220;X people drive like this, but Y people drive like that.&amp;#8221; Rather, I&amp;#8217;m asking you to accept that there are things that you do, say, think, believe, know, understand, value, engage in, and so on that you share with some people and not others.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And when I ask about decorum, I&amp;#8217;m asking you to explore what you share. For the people with whom you share this thing, how do you talk? How do you use language among yourselves? Are there things you know that other people don&amp;#8217;t? Are there things that you all might notice that an outsider might not? Are there things that you had to learn when you first joined this community? Were there mistakes you made that you wouldn&amp;#8217;t make now? Are there things that you expect of each other in&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;Because at its worst, what we mean when we say &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t want to put labels on people&amp;#8221; is &amp;#8220;I haven&amp;#8217;t actually stopped dating my ex.&amp;#8221;&lt;/span&gt; It&amp;#8217;s a relationship cliche that &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t want to put a label on this&amp;#8221; is just another way of saying &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m unwilling to commit,&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;I&amp;#8217;m excluding myself from this label because I want the benefits it implies, but not the obligations.&amp;#8221; When we refuse to add labels to who we are, we&amp;#8217;re refusing to recognize any commonality&amp;#8212;or at least, any nameable commonality&amp;#8212;with anyone. When my son calls me &amp;#8220;Dad,&amp;#8221; he labels me. To deny the label is to deny something essential about who we are to&amp;nbsp;one&amp;nbsp;another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to swing this back around to the practical: consider yourself. If you want to avoid the essentializing impulse of labels, consider first what you do. Activities you like. Habits. Interests. Hobbies. Are there things that you do that you share with some people in your life, but not others? Don&amp;#8217;t think about labels. Think about those people. What do you share with them? What are the samenesses that come from this common pursuit? And what among those samenesses is invisible, secret, obscure, or obfuscated to those who do not share it? If there is commonality, there is a community, and thus is a group and a culture&amp;#8212;whether you choose to hang a label on it&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anybody&amp;#8217;s running a pool on &amp;#8220;most pretentious sentences on this website&lt;a href=&#34;http://geekabouttown.com/posts/omc-must-be-stopped#fn:1&#34;&gt;,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; this is definitely a contender.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At any moment we are using language we must say or write the right thing in the right way while playing the right social role and (appearing) to hold the right values, beliefs, and attitudes. Thus, what is important is not language, and surely not grammar, but &lt;em&gt;saying (writing)-doing-being-valuing-believing combinations.&lt;/em&gt; These combinations I call &amp;#8220;Discourses&amp;#8221; &amp;#8230;. Discourses are ways of being in the world; they are forms of life which integrate words, acts, values, beliefs, attitudes, and social identities as well as gestures, glances, body positions,&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;clothes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;James Gee, &amp;#8220;Literacy, Discourse, and Linguistics: Introduction,&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;Journal of Education&lt;/em&gt; 171.1 (1989).&lt;/cite&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">OMC must be stopped!</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/omc-must-be-stopped"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/omc-must-be-stopped</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This post is egregiously unfair to essayist &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.justinstgermain.com/&#34;&gt;Justin St. Germain&lt;/a&gt;, who I do not know. I&amp;#8217;m sure he&amp;#8217;s a wonderful person, but he sure as hell backed the wrong horse here I&amp;nbsp;tell&amp;nbsp;you&amp;nbsp;what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before the election, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radiolab.org/story/one-vote/&#34;&gt;Radiolab&lt;/a&gt; ran an episode seeking out those mythical moments where one vote made a difference. They did it too early.  On March 3, something went badly wrong with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;March Fadness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in a way which arguably speaks to the fundamental failure of democracy in which we are all immersed. Specifically: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/past-games/#/omcvsmarccohn/&#34;&gt;Marc Cohn&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Walking in Memphis&amp;#8221; lost to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;How Bizarre&amp;#8221; by one vote&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar with &lt;em&gt;March Fadness,&lt;/em&gt; the tournament&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/wtf/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;WTF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;page&amp;nbsp;explains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;March Fadness&lt;/em&gt; features one-hit wonders of the 1990s pitted against each other in ridiculous and possibly pointless games, all in search of understanding the 1990s and its culture as well as the uses and failures&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what makes &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; particularly beautiful, I think: it suggests that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.dailymail.co.uk/i/pix/2013/01/16/article-2263127-16F73FEA000005DC-186_634x822.jpg&#34;&gt;ridiculousness of the 1990s&lt;/a&gt; can somehow give rise to an understanding of ourselves and our culture&amp;#8212;that, say, asking us to choose between &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/#/skeelovshaddaway/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;I Wish&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;What Is Love&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; can give us a way of examining the gaps between who we are now and who we were then. The tournament assumes that the question asked in each round&amp;#8212;&amp;#8221;Which song is the best?&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;means something bigger and deeper than its simple&amp;nbsp;wording&amp;nbsp;implies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come with me this far, at least: &lt;em&gt;March Fadness&lt;/em&gt; is in truth an essay made of essays, a great metaekphrasis&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; using art and memory to heighten and sharpen one another&amp;#8217;s mystery. &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;March Fadness&lt;/em&gt; is rooted in a belief that art&amp;#8212;even the one-hit wonders of the 90s&amp;#8212;offers access&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;humanity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These votes are immensely complex; if two of us vote for the same song, can we say with any certainty that those two votes mean the same thing? We cannot. Are people voting for the songs? For the videos? For the memories? For the essays? For the essayists? For the preservation of their own brackets? Or &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; any of those things, as I always root for whoever the Jets are playing?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Or do all these strands braid around the maypole of a single radio button? Can we have a meaningful conversation about &amp;#8220;which song is the best&amp;#8221; if we are not in communion about what purpose&amp;nbsp;art&amp;nbsp;serves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last question is why Justin St. Germain&amp;#8212;and, by extension, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;How Bizarre&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;must&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;stopped. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. Germain begins his essay by explicitly discarding the idea of aesthetics, observing that the alleged experts walking the halls of museums seem to have differing standards for interpreting art. His response is personal: &amp;#8220;I mostly just like to stare at it for a while, and see if I can see the genius.&amp;#8221; The conclusion this points toward is that exposure is &amp;#8220;all you really need to formulate some aesthetics.&amp;#8221; The feeling I get&amp;#8212;which, I think, pervades his essay&amp;#8212;is that because there are so many standards, aesthetics must be subjective, and that if aesthetics are subjective, they must therefore be personal and individual. &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know whether Justin St. Germain is a climate denier, but this is certainly the climate denier&amp;#8217;s stance.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;There are conflicting opinions; therefore, all opinions must be&amp;nbsp;equally&amp;nbsp;valid.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, his argument is rooted in the personal: &amp;#8220;Quick,&amp;#8221; he asks, &amp;#8220;what does &amp;#8216;How Bizarre&amp;#8217; remind you of?&amp;#8221; What makes art valuable&amp;#8212;or, at least, what makes the art of 90s one-hit wonders valuable&amp;#8212;is how powerfully it is linked to his personal memories. He attempts to colonize ours, too; despite what St. Germain seems to think, I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; have any of &amp;#8220;How Bizarre&amp;#8221; memorized, except for the words &amp;#8220;How Bizarre.&amp;#8221; He glances back briefly at the question of aesthetics, but only sarcastically. He winks at some metrics of value&amp;#8212;&amp;#8221;How Bizarre&amp;#8221; was popular; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has an interesting story; one specific image and line from the video resonates in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barnum_effect&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Barnum&lt;/a&gt; sort of way with current events&amp;#8212;but he does not seriously engage them as ways of comparing. (&amp;#8220;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is better because of the story&amp;#8221; works only if it is held up against Mark Cohn&amp;#8217;s story, or Donna Lewis&amp;#8217;s, or&amp;nbsp;Harvey&amp;nbsp;Danger&amp;#8217;s.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this points toward a solipsistic, cynical view of human endeavor, but what bothers me most are the constant jabs at &amp;#8220;Walking in Memphis.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s not on Memphis&amp;#8217;s wikipedia page, hurr hurr. There&amp;#8217;s not a book about it, hurr hurr. It doesn&amp;#8217;t belong in the National Gallery, hurr hurr. As &amp;#8220;How Bizarre&amp;#8221; has advanced through the tournament, these snarklets have been tweaked to address each opponent, revealing how little merit they have. These digs are superficial and even nonsensical&amp;#8212;will &amp;#8220;How Bizarre&amp;#8221; end up in the National Gallery?&amp;#8212;but they all speak to a way of thinking about art that I find deeply unsettling: &lt;em&gt;my thing is good because I like it, and therefore I denigrate your thing without attempting to&amp;nbsp;understanding&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Walking in Memphis,&amp;#8221; on the other hand, reaches right into the heart of what &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is supposed to be about. St. Germain may discard or trivialize aesthetics for &amp;#8220;Bizarre,&amp;#8221; but &amp;#8220;Memphis&amp;#8221; is itself an argument about the purpose of art: for Cohn, the honest, wholehearted pursuit of art is the pathway to&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;divine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her essay, Lisa M. O&amp;#8217;Neill argues that &amp;#8220;Memphis&amp;#8221; is a celebration of earnestness,&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;might:&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only every so often as adults do we experience—do we allow ourselves to experience—what this earnestness feels like. When we free ourselves from posturing as experts. Every single one of us knows what it is to sing with all our might. Belting out the notes. Holding nothing back. Pouring every iota of ourselves into the song. All&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;striving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story she tells of the song&amp;#8212;which, St. Germain&amp;#8217;s glibness notwithstanding, unquestionably &amp;#8220;wins on pathos&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;is one of a man searching for the best of his art, following a holy man on a pilgrim&amp;#8217;s path, seeking contact with something greater&amp;nbsp;than&amp;nbsp;himself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&#34;https://genius.com/Marc-cohn-walking-in-memphis-lyrics&#34;&gt;the song itself&lt;/a&gt; is liturgy: Cohn puts on his blue-suede vestments. He invites the protection of Saint Handy. He walks the Stations of the Cross&amp;#8212;remember, he&amp;#8217;s a Christian tonight&amp;#8212;stopping for a moment to reflect on each holy site. Graceland. The Hollywood.  Amid the rising incense of gospel, he comes to the Lord&amp;#8217;s Table for communion, and Reverend Green offers him a holier substance&amp;nbsp;than&amp;nbsp;bread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threaded throughout, the question: &amp;#8220;do I really feel the way&amp;nbsp;I&amp;nbsp;feel?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;Walking in Memphis&amp;#8221; is a statement of faith: that if there is anything out there, beyond the borders of this world, it is through art that we will someday reach it.&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;Memphis&amp;#8221; is Cohn trying to reach through the city to the beyond, to make sense of loss, of pain, of death. The ghost of Elvis his Beatrice, his Paradise the Jungle Room, music his vehicle to&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;numinous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Walking in Memphis&amp;#8221; absolutely should have won. When I voted, &amp;#8220;Memphis&amp;#8221; was well behind &amp;#8220;Bizarre,&amp;#8221; and I thought briefly about whether I should vote on other devices. That would clearly be wrong,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but I wish I&amp;#8217;d cheated, just a little, so Cohn&amp;#8217;s pilgrimage could have taken him&amp;#8212;and us&amp;#8212;just a&amp;nbsp;bit&amp;nbsp;farther.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, it comes down to this: Lisa M. O&amp;#8217;Neill was asking, &amp;#8220;Does &amp;#8216;Walking in Memphis&amp;#8217; speak to the best of humanity?&amp;#8221; Justin St. Germain was asking, &amp;#8220;Was &amp;#8216;How Bizarre&amp;#8217; playing on my stolen boombox while I felt up Shelly Wallace in the back of my Ranchero?&amp;#8221;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I don&amp;#8217;t care so much that Mark Cohn lost to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, but I do care that people who ask the first kind of question lost to people who ask the second.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St. Germain and &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OMC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; are now facing The Proclaimers&amp;#8217; &amp;#8220;500 Miles&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;another earnest journey&amp;#8212;in the Elite 8. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/#/proclaimersvsomc/&#34;&gt;Go vote&amp;nbsp;against&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited 3/24/17 9:25 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to add: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/past-games/#/proclaimersvsomc/&#34;&gt;Noooooooooooo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited 3/28/17 9:15 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to add: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marchfadness.com/past-games/#/omcvschumbawamba/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NOOOOOOOOOOOO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost certainly the most pretentious term I have ever used in my life. At least I didn&amp;#8217;t say &lt;span class=&#39;serif&#39;&gt;μετάἐκφράσις&lt;/span&gt;?&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems a more effective way to be a Dolphins fan than rooting &lt;em&gt;for&lt;/em&gt; the Dolphins.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although something about the feel of his essay suggests that St. Germain maybe voted for himself eight times.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stolen boombox is canon, but Shelly Wallace and the Ranchero are speculation.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;St. Germain&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://thediagram.com/17_1/stgermain.html&#34;&gt;recent essay on &amp;#8220;The Regulators&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;Diagram&lt;/em&gt; is fantastic, and completely inconsistent with the criticism I&amp;#8217;m levying here. Read it and love it.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">On Microwaves and Human Dignity</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/on-microwaves-and-human-dignity"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/on-microwaves-and-human-dignity</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;One of the ongoing questions under discussion at my college these days is this: how can we best make use of our&amp;nbsp;embedded&amp;nbsp;tutors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In answer to that question, I offer the following email conversation held between myself and my Augmented Instruction tutor&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it will offer some valuable insight into the relationship between instructor and&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Mar 14, 2017 12:01 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &amp;#8220;Joshua Geist&amp;#8221; &lt;a href=&#34;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#60;&amp;#106;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#97;&amp;#115;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;#106;&amp;#110;&amp;#105;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#97;&amp;#115;&amp;#103;&amp;#101;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to your spam-Add-Minute-and-wait-till-it-feels-done approach to timing, it occurred to me that perhaps not everybody gets frustrated that their microwave timer can&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;half-seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tue, Mar 14, 2017 at 12:49 &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, Redacted Redacted &amp;lt;redacted@redacted.redacted&amp;gt;&amp;nbsp;wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am glad to get this email&amp;#8212; I was worried that still thinking about microwaves the whole drive back to Visalia&amp;nbsp;was&amp;nbsp;abnormal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, productive. I have concluded that the level of efficiency in the usage of microwave buttons is dependent on how much time you need something cooked for, due to the nature of the buttons. I argue that anything that will be cooked for four minutes or less should be cooked using the &amp;#8220;add&amp;nbsp;minute&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;button.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in our example, we have two&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1) Put in the amount of time you need, directly. This&amp;nbsp;formula&amp;nbsp;is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[cook time]+[minute]+[second]+[second]+[start]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree with you on this in general, but some microwaves&amp;#8212;microwaves which, to my mind, are vastly superior to the more common designs&amp;#8212;assume that numeric input &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; cook time, which it obviously should be. That&amp;#8217;s what a microwave is &lt;em&gt;for,&lt;/em&gt; right? If I push &lt;code&gt;[1][3][0]&lt;/code&gt;, is there any better interpretation than that that is cook time? There is not. What, is my microwave also a remote control for my &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;? Am I using it to dial my phone? &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. I am using it to&amp;nbsp;cook&amp;nbsp;food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly (for the below), if our microwave eschews the ludicrous Cook Time button, &lt;code&gt;[9][9]&lt;/code&gt; refers unambiguously to one minute and&amp;nbsp;39&amp;nbsp;seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this formula, we are assuming you know, to the second, how much time you require, so there is no need to cancel out remaining time. Also, there is the option of adding another button under &lt;code&gt;[minute]&lt;/code&gt;, but that doesn&amp;#8217;t come into play in&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2) Use the &amp;#8220;add minute&amp;#8221; option, and, of course, cancel out leftover time.&amp;nbsp;This&amp;nbsp;gives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[add minute]x+[cancel]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;X&amp;#8221; in this equation is the amount of minutes you are adding, obviously, and therefore must be a positive, whole number. Because the &amp;#8220;add minute&amp;#8221; button begins the microwave automatically, we remove both the &amp;#8220;cook time&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;start&amp;#8221; variables. However, we do add in the need to cancel out&amp;nbsp;old&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A minor objection: in most cases, the first press of &lt;code&gt;Cancel&lt;/code&gt; will stop the microwave, meaning that you have to press &lt;code&gt;Cancel&lt;/code&gt; again to clear the remaining time. I would submit that this&amp;nbsp;should&amp;nbsp;read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[Add Minute]x + [Cancel] + [Cancel]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you could open the door while it&amp;#8217;s running, but this is most likely dangerous, and at the very&amp;nbsp;least&amp;nbsp;distasteful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion? The original formula requires the pressing of five-six buttons, total. Five is the minimum amount of buttons to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;pressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second formula, two is the minimum amount of buttons to be pressed, if x is equal to 1, and can be up to 100, if x is equal to 99 (an argument could be made that it will take over a minute to press &amp;#8220;add minute&amp;#8221; 99 times, therefore the maximum could be increased. But this is a&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;argument).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, if 1≤x≤4, the second formula will be equally or more efficient than the first, because in those cases it would only require the pressing of two-five&amp;nbsp;buttons,&amp;nbsp;total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On an ideal microwave&amp;#8212;which &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; exist; the microwave in the lunchroom at the Hanford Center works this way (and yes I will bring it to class for a demonstration if need be)&amp;#8212;the math&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1-9 seconds: I think we can stipulate that microwaving something for less than ten seconds is stupid; just hold it in the sun for a second&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10&amp;nbsp;seconds-60&amp;nbsp;seconds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[6][0][start] = 3 buttons
[AM][Cancel][Cancel] = 3 buttons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;61&amp;nbsp;seconds-99&amp;nbsp;seconds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[9][9][start] = 3 buttons
[AM][AM][Cancel][Cancel] = 4 buttons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1:39-3:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[3][0][0][start] = 4 buttons
[AM][AM][AM][Cancel][Cancel] = 5 buttons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3:01-4:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[4][0][0][start] = 4 buttons
[AM][AM][AM][AM][Cancel][Cancel] = 6 buttons
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And sadly it&amp;#8217;s all downhill&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we add in the sadly-prevalent &lt;code&gt;[Cook Time]&lt;/code&gt;, this means that there is one case&amp;#8212;10-60 seconds&amp;#8212;where using the &lt;code&gt;[Add Minute]&lt;/code&gt; approach is more efficient. However, I would argue that trying to optimize that situation is foolish; the obvious approach is to go out and buy a better-designed microwave. Any time and opportunity cost therein incurred would be made up almost immediately by the button-press&amp;nbsp;time&amp;nbsp;savings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you value efficiency above your own dignity and above the needs of others, you could omit the second &lt;code&gt;[Cancel]&lt;/code&gt; press in the &lt;code&gt;[Add Minute]&lt;/code&gt; approach and leave your leftover filthy shame seconds for others to see and know, which certainly changes the&amp;nbsp;equation&amp;nbsp;somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But given an ideal microwave, the add minute approach is almost always worse than specifying&amp;nbsp;cook&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus there is less distance to move your fingers when repeatedly hitting one button up to four times, and less eye-search and mental processing time and power required. But that&amp;#8217;s another&amp;nbsp;point&amp;nbsp;altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me finally add that these calculations leave out the moral and emotional aspects of this process. Certainly, we can reduce microwaving to a question of mere efficiency, but this loses all of the complicated nuance of the task. How does one account for the feeling of pride one gets with a careful, accurate estimation? How does one factor in the way the food tastes just a little bit better knowing that its perfect temperature is the result of my own insight and forethought, rather than haphazard button-slapping? How too the knowledge that those who share the microwave with me will feel my respect and admiration manifested in a&amp;nbsp;clean&amp;nbsp;timer?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These things are worth a little lost efficiency, to my mind. Honor the human soul within you. We are better than &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scientific_management&#34;&gt;Taylorism&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quod&amp;nbsp;erat&amp;nbsp;demonstrandum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">The Phenomenology of Purpose</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/the-phenomenology-of-purpose"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/the-phenomenology-of-purpose</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;A colleague sent me an email recently asking a question which initially I felt like I didn&amp;#8217;t understand. As I meditated on it, though, I found that my lack of understanding was deeper, richer, and more complex than I had at first appreciated. It speaks to some of the fundamental complexities of teaching writing, and just beneath its surface lurks some of my most passionate&amp;#8212;and sometimes most aggressively expressed&amp;#8212;beliefs about what the teaching of writing&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you negotiate &amp;#8230; the conflicts/tensions between student purposes in their writing and the purposes we assume they have to learn about in&amp;nbsp;academic&amp;nbsp;writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow me to interrogate your slash. Does it stand for &amp;#8220;or?&amp;#8221; Does it stand for &lt;em&gt;beziehungsweise?&lt;/em&gt; Does it clarify? Tension is not always conflict. Think &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tensegrity&#34;&gt;tensegrity&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://static.panoramio.com/photos/large/62016957.jpg&#34;&gt;impossible things&lt;/a&gt; stand tall because their tension balances them. Tension is sometimes harmony, or at least tension can sometimes&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;harmonized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is tension, too, in your phrasing. &amp;#8220;We assume,&amp;#8221; implying we are not certain. &amp;#8220;Have to learn,&amp;#8221; as distinct from &amp;#8220;need to learn&amp;#8221;&amp;#8212;itself distinct from &amp;#8220;need&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;know.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here, I think, you are speaking to the haze in which we operate as writing teachers. The naïve (to my mind) way of approaching writing instruction is to take for granted that as an experienced writer and certificated expert, I know the forms and purposes that students will need, and it is my job to ensure that my students conform to those forms and purposes. There must be a thesis statement, which must look like &lt;em&gt;this,&lt;/em&gt; and go &lt;em&gt;here,&lt;/em&gt; and contain &lt;em&gt;these components.&lt;/em&gt; Source X is valid support because it has 4 of the 7 features on my official list&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;support-validating-features. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But of course it is my general belief that whenever we think we know something for sure, it is simply because we haven&amp;#8217;t paid close&amp;nbsp;enough&amp;nbsp;attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A Digression&amp;nbsp;into&amp;nbsp;Error&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Joseph Williams&amp;#8217;s seminal essay &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/356689?origin=JSTOR-pdf&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;The Phenomenology of Error,&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; he notes that in order for a grammatical error to exist in student writing, it must exist in at least five places along two axes. First, the error must&amp;nbsp;exist&amp;nbsp;in &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the student&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;paper,&amp;nbsp;and &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the student&amp;#8217;s mind (i.e., a typo is not&amp;nbsp;an&amp;nbsp;error).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the error must&amp;nbsp;exist&amp;nbsp;in &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;3&#34;&gt;the mind of the grammarian who identified the&amp;nbsp;rule,&amp;nbsp;and &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;4&#34;&gt;the text in which the grammarian recorded&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;rule. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two axes&amp;nbsp;intersect&amp;nbsp;at &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;5&#34;&gt;the mind of the reader, who connects the error in the student&amp;#8217;s text (and thus the writer&amp;#8217;s mind) with the error in the handbook (and thus the&amp;nbsp;grammarian&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;mind). &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;williams&#39;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script type=&#34;text/coffeescript&#34;&gt;
    $ -&gt;
        $(&#39;#williams&#39;).css({position: &#34;relative&#34;, width: &#39;100%&#39;, height: &#39;400px&#39;})

        williams = 
            pointsize: 3
            board: JXG.JSXGraph.initBoard &#39;williams&#39;,
                    boundingbox: [0, 10, 10, 0]
                    axis:false

            coords:
                writer: [2, 9]
                text: [4, 7]
                grammarian: [2, 1]
                handbook: [4, 3]
                instructor: [6, 5]

            makepoints: -&gt;
                @points =
                    writer: @board.create &#39;point&#39;, @coords.writer, 
                        name: &#34;Writer&#34;
                        size:@pointsize
                        color: &#39;#00AA00&#39;
                    text: @board.create &#39;point&#39;, @coords.text, 
                        name: &#34;Text&#34;, 
                        size:@pointsize, 
                        color: &#39;#00AA00&#39;
                    grammarian: @board.create &#39;point&#39;, @coords.grammarian, 
                        name: &#34;Grammarian&#34; 
                        size:@pointsize
                        color: &#39;#0000AA&#39;
                        label:
                            offset: [10, -10]
                    handbook: @board.create &#39;point&#39;, @coords.handbook, 
                        name: &#34;Handbook&#34; 
                        size:@pointsize 
                        color: &#39;#0000AA&#39;
                        label: 
                            offset: [10, -10]
                    instructor: @board.create &#39;point&#39;, @coords.instructor, {name: &#34;Reader&#34;, size:@pointsize, color: &#39;#00AAAA&#39;}

            drawlines: -&gt;
                @lines = 
                    essay: @board.create &#39;line&#39;, [@points.writer, @points.instructor], 
                        color: &#39;#00AA00&#39;
                        straightFirst: false
                        straightLast: false
                    grammar: @board.create &#39;line&#39;, [@points.grammarian, @points.instructor], 
                        color: &#39;#0000AA&#39;
                        straightFirst: false
                        straightLast: false

        williams.makepoints()
        williams.drawlines()
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this sounds complicated, that is because it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; complicated&amp;#8212;but its complexity is hidden by the ease and comfort with which most experienced native-language readers occupy position 5, and by the fact that position 5 is the intersection of those axes. In other words: when we see an error in student writing, it is easy to think the error is &lt;em&gt;here,&lt;/em&gt; and to forget that it stretches out in one direction through the paper into the mind of the student, and in another direction through (say) &lt;em&gt;The Elements of Style&lt;/em&gt; into the mind of E.&amp;nbsp;B.&amp;nbsp;White.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea&amp;#8212;that a concept like error is a collision of abstractions located in different physical and cognitive spaces&amp;#8212;is, I think, lurking beneath&amp;nbsp;your&amp;nbsp;question. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Phenomenology&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is &amp;#8220;purpose&amp;#8221; in a piece of classroom writing? I think it&amp;#8217;s more complicated even than Williams&amp;#8217;s model&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, we sit at the intersection. We look off in one direction toward&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;student: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;what does the student &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;accomplish? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how does the paper manifest&amp;nbsp;that&amp;nbsp;purpose? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another, we&amp;nbsp;look&amp;nbsp;inward: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;3&#34;&gt;what do I, as instructor, want students to accomplish in this assignment&amp;#8212;and we might forget that the path to that purpose&amp;nbsp;passes&amp;nbsp;through &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;4&#34;&gt;how effectively do I explain that purpose in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;prompt? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a third direction, we look toward the academy, where the road forks. We first&amp;nbsp;pass&amp;nbsp;through &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;5&#34;&gt;what purposes are declared in the Course Outline for the course I am teaching? This is, of course, meant&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;reflect &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;6&#34;&gt;our institutional beliefs about what students need to know about academic writing. But there&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;also &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li value=&#34;7&#34;&gt;what actual academic writers do, which &lt;em&gt;only occasionally&amp;nbsp;resembles&amp;nbsp;1-6.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;And it&amp;nbsp;gets&amp;nbsp;worse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phenomenological geometry of purpose is, I think, more complex than that of error because it is also &lt;em&gt;time-bound.&lt;/em&gt; If you have Javascript enabled, the below should animate things nicely; if not, hopefully it will still make a measure of sense. (Click on the buttons following each paragraph below, assuming&amp;nbsp;they&amp;nbsp;exist.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;purpose&#39;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div id=&#39;hideme&#39;&gt;

&lt;p class=&#34;start&#34;&gt;First, we imagine a type of academic writing which we would like to see from our students. &lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;PromptTarget&#39;&gt;》&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;PromptTarget&#34;&gt;&lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;start&#39;&gt;《&lt;/button&gt; In imagining it, we reach toward the point where it lives&amp;#8212;in the world of academic writing, real or imagined, hopefully brought into range by way of the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;COR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. We write a prompt which, we hope, will invite that type of writing&amp;#8212;as an archer draws a bead on a distant target.&lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;PromptSolid&#39;&gt;》&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;PromptSolid&#34;&gt;&lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;PromptTarget&#39;&gt;《&lt;/button&gt; Our prompt may not actually point toward the kind of purpose we hope it will, of course; nonetheless, as prompts are visible to students in ways our inmost thoughts are not, they define what students aim for. &lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;StudentTarget&#39;&gt;》&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;StudentTarget&#34;&gt;&lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;PromptSolid&#39;&gt;《&lt;/button&gt; Once our students receive our prompts, they too have to craft a purpose which, they think, aligns with the purpose we have staked out for them. &lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;StudentSolid&#39;&gt;》&lt;/button&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;StudentSolid&#34;&gt;&lt;button class=&#39;parbutton&#39; data-step=&#39;StudentTarget&#39;&gt;《&lt;/button&gt; Their essays represent their attempts, just as our prompts represent our attempts, to make real a particular kind of (authentic or synthetic)&amp;nbsp;academic&amp;nbsp;purpose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Locating&amp;nbsp;our&amp;nbsp;purpose&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what are we supposed to do? If we acknowledge that the concept of &amp;#8220;purpose&amp;#8221; within the space of the college writing classroom is this complex, multidimensional thing, what do we&amp;nbsp;teach&amp;nbsp;students?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lift&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;curtain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we must be honest about what we are doing. When we write assignments, we are trying to describe a particular kind of purpose which we perceive to be consistent with academic writing. That act of description is casting a ray into the field of possibility&amp;#8212;but it is not the full range of that possibility. I think we should engage that with&amp;nbsp;our&amp;nbsp;students. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I was talking to my class about the assignment we&amp;#8217;re currently working on. I&amp;#8217;ve told them before that this is a new prompt, and that we should think about it as a starting point. In discussing it together, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to revise and refine the purpose I have for them &lt;em&gt;in front of them,&lt;/em&gt; so that they can see both where I&amp;#8217;m standing and what I&amp;#8217;m pointing toward. Today, we talked about how this specific assignment&amp;#8212;analyzing the representation of the ghetto presented in a hip hop song from a historical perspective&amp;#8212;is artificial, but that the purposes represented within it are real within the space of academic writing. The idea of using one text (i.e., our historical readings) as a lens through which to analyze another (i.e., the song in question) is a very academic task, even within an&amp;nbsp;artificial&amp;nbsp;space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In having that conversation, I hope that my students caught a glimpse into the field of academic possibility. This move represents a kind of thing they can do to accomplish a kind of purpose that exists within the space of&amp;nbsp;academic&amp;nbsp;writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Teach targeting, not&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;target&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we acknowledge that academic purposes are diverse, and in many cases unfamiliar to us, then we must necessarily acknowledge that we cannot teach our students all academic purposes. I&amp;#8217;ve never written a case study for &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;JAMA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; nor an analysis of the decay rate of Uranium, nor a billion other things in disciplines other than my own. I can&amp;#8217;t teach my students those things. And I&amp;#8217;m not really supposed to&amp;#8212;I&amp;#8217;m teaching an introduction to academic writing, not a graduate-level writing class within a discipline. But I feel like it&amp;#8217;s important for us to remember that those purposes are out there, in our&amp;nbsp;students&amp;#8217;&amp;nbsp;futures. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we teach only the kind of academic purposes with which we are most familiar, or only those purposes which &amp;#8220;we assume they have to learn about in academic writing,&amp;#8221; we prepare them to work toward those&amp;nbsp;purposes&amp;nbsp;alone. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my English 1, I teach &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; style. The &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;COR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; says I&amp;#8217;m supposed to, and it&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;m most familiar with. But most of my students won&amp;#8217;t be literature critics, which means that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; style will fall out of use very quickly for them. So I position both &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and myself differently. I tell them that we are not learning &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; style. Rather, we are learning &lt;em&gt;how to learn a new citation style.&lt;/em&gt; What questions to ask of a new style guide, and how to find the answers. What kinds of things a citation style might describe. We are learning &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; style as a byproduct of learning how to do this kind&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this should also be how we approach the vast field of academic purposes. We should not be telling students &amp;#8220;this is how you do it,&amp;#8221; or even &amp;#8220;this is what you&amp;#8217;re supposed to do.&amp;#8221; We should be teaching them &lt;em&gt;how to figure out what they&amp;#8217;re supposed to do.&lt;/em&gt; How to identify the task and the kind of purpose being called for by a new assignment. How to read in a new discipline to identify the conventions of that discipline. How to understand the expectations and needs of our audience. How to craft a text which brings their own purpose into alignment with the purposes valued by the discipline in which they are writing. All of this is, of course, an extremely convoluted way to say that we should teach writing as rhetorical&amp;#8212;but I think it is easy to pay lipservice to that idea, and to forget the complex reality which it seeks&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say this more simply: our goal is not just to teach students to work toward the kind of purpose we believe they should be working toward, but rather to make choices about their purpose which allows them to align with the purposes their audiences will be&amp;nbsp;amenable&amp;nbsp;to. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we hold to the model of writing as archery, with students&amp;#8217; essays representing shots at the hazy, moving target as academic writing, then we should care less about the target they are aiming at than we do about teaching them how&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;And&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;warning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we must must &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; imagine ourselves to be entities who live at the Intersection. Moreover, we must not conflate the Intersection with the Real Academy. What I mean by this more concretely is that we shouldn&amp;#8217;t let ourselves get too comfortable with the idea that we know what kinds of writing students will need, or that we have communicated those purposes to them in a way that is clear and distinct. Of course, we &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; more familiar with academic writing than our students, but it is so easy to reduce the vast field of possibility within that space into a&amp;nbsp;single&amp;nbsp;point. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That point is important and powerful. The Intersection&amp;#8212;where our students&amp;#8217; purposes, our own purposes, and the purposes we know and imagine in the academy collide&amp;#8212;is where we spend a lot of our time. It is and must be where evaluation happens, and it is good to sit there for a time and look at where we are, right now, in this moment. Is this essay doing what it&amp;#8217;s supposed to be doing? We should care&amp;nbsp;about&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practicing archery, the target is of course important&amp;#8212;but most of one&amp;#8217;s time is spent at the line, loosing volley after volley at that target. We visit the target to see how we&amp;#8217;ve done, and to gather our arrows, and then we return to the line to practice&amp;nbsp;our&amp;nbsp;aim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should visit the Intersection, but we should not build a&amp;nbsp;house&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&#34;text/coffeescript&#34;&gt;
    $ -&gt;
        $(&#39;#purpose&#39;).css({position: &#34;relative&#34;, width: &#39;100%&#39;, height: &#39;300px&#39;, &#39;margin-top&#39;: &#39;1em&#39;, &#39;margin-bottom&#39;: &#39;1em&#39;})

        purpose = 
            pointsize: 3
            board: JXG.JSXGraph.initBoard &#39;purpose&#39;,
                    boundingbox: [0, 10, 10, 0]
                    axis:false

            coords: [
                [&#39;Instructor&#39;, [2, 1], &#39;#00AA00&#39;],
                [&#39;Prompt&#39;, [5, 2], &#39;#00AA00&#39;],
                [&#39;COR&#39;, [8, 5], &#39;#FF8800&#39;],
                [&#39;The Real Academy&#39;, [7, 9], &#39;#FF8800&#39;],
                [&#39;The Imagined Academy&#39;, [9, 9], &#39;#FF8800&#39;],
                [&#39;Student&#39;, [2, 9], &#39;#0000AA&#39;],
                [&#39;Essay&#39;, [4, 7], &#39;#0000AA&#39;],
                [&#39;Intersection&#39;, [8, 3], &#39;#AAAAAA&#39;],
            ]

            linecoords: [
                [&#39;Acad1&#39;, [&#39;COR&#39;, &#39;The Real Academy&#39;], &#39;#FF8800&#39;, 0],
                [&#39;Acad2&#39;, [&#39;COR&#39;, &#39;The Imagined Academy&#39;], &#39;#FF8800&#39;, 0],
                [&#39;Acad3&#39;, [&#39;COR&#39;, &#39;Intersection&#39;], &#39;#FF8800&#39;, 0],
                [&#39;PromptTarget&#39;, [&#39;Instructor&#39;, &#39;Intersection&#39;], &#39;#00AA00&#39;, 1],
                [&#39;PromptSolid&#39;, [&#39;Instructor&#39;, &#39;Intersection&#39;], &#39;#00AA00&#39;, 0],
                [&#39;StudentTarget&#39;, [&#39;Student&#39;, &#39;Intersection&#39;], &#39;#0000AA&#39;, 1],
                [&#39;StudentSolid&#39;, [&#39;Student&#39;, &#39;Intersection&#39;], &#39;#0000AA&#39;, 0],

            ]

            points: {}
            lines: {}

            makepoint: (item) -&gt;
                @points[item[0]] = @board.create &#39;point&#39;, item[1], 
                    name: item[0]
                    size: @pointsize
                    color: item[2]

            makepoints: -&gt;
                @makepoint item for item in @coords    
                @points[&#39;Prompt&#39;].hideElement()
                @points[&#39;Essay&#39;].hideElement()

            drawline: (item) -&gt;
                @lines[item[0]] = @board.create &#39;line&#39;, [@points[item[1][0]], @points[item[1][1]]], 
                        color: item[2],
                        straightFirst: false,
                        straightLast: false,
                        dash: item[3],
                        visible: false

            drawlines:  -&gt;
                @drawline item for item in @linecoords    
                @lines[item].showElement() for item in [&#39;Acad1&#39;, &#39;Acad2&#39;, &#39;Acad3&#39;]

            dostep: (event) -&gt;
                action = $(event.target).attr(&#39;data-step&#39;)
                $(&#39;#hideme p&#39;).hide()
                $(&#39;#hideme p.&#39; + action).show()

                switch action
                    when &#34;start&#34;
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptSolid&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Prompt&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptTarget&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentTarget&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Essay&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentSolid&#39;].hideElement()
                    when &#34;PromptTarget&#34;
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptSolid&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Prompt&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptTarget&#39;].showElement()
                    when &#34;PromptSolid&#34;
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptTarget&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Prompt&#39;].showElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;PromptSolid&#39;].showElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentTarget&#39;].hideElement()
                    when &#34;StudentTarget&#34;
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentTarget&#39;].showElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Essay&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentSolid&#39;].hideElement()
                    when &#34;StudentSolid&#34;
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentTarget&#39;].hideElement()
                        purpose.points[&#39;Essay&#39;].showElement()
                        purpose.lines[&#39;StudentSolid&#39;].showElement()

        purpose.makepoints()
        purpose.drawlines()

        $(&#39;.parbutton&#39;).show().click purpose.dostep
        $(&#39;#hideme p:not(.start)&#39;).hide()

&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;style type=&#39;text/css&#39;&gt;
    button {
        display: none;
    }
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">A Collection of Oddities</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/a-collection-of-oddities"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/a-collection-of-oddities</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past while, I&amp;#8217;ve kind of vanished from the internet.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Back in the day, though, I used to do some cool stuff, especially for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://killscreen.com/author/j-nicholas-geist/&#34;&gt;Kill Screen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; A lot of the stuff I did is broken now, with only a blank page where something neat used to be. For a while, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; tried to wrestle my mostly bad code into submission with each website update, but there&amp;#8217;s only so much effort one can reasonably expect even &lt;em&gt;Kill Screen&amp;#8217;s&lt;/em&gt; awesome web team to put in micromanaging six-year-old structure-dependent javascript based on absurdly outdated versions of assorted offsite libraries. So mostly, my history at &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is full&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I get emails or twitter mentions from other people who also thought some of my web experiments at &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://killscreen.com/author/j-nicholas-geist/&#34;&gt;Kill Screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; were neat, and wondering where they are. So (with &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8216;s permission) I&amp;#8217;m republishing &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/&#34;&gt;some of those oddities here&lt;/a&gt;. The first of them is one of my favorite things I&amp;#8217;ve ever written, my review of &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/infinity-blade/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinity Blade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m glad it&amp;#8217;s back&amp;nbsp;up&amp;nbsp;somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the notable exception of posting needlessly in-depth responses to irrelevant questions on esoteric subreddits, of course.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Audiobooks and the Platonic Story</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Spoiler&amp;nbsp;Alert&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following contains minor plot spoilers for John Ajvide Lindqvist&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Let the Right One In&lt;/em&gt; and Brandon Sanderson&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Mistborn&lt;/em&gt; trilogy. I&amp;#8217;ve veiled the details as much as possible, but if you&amp;#8217;re wanting to remain pristine, you might want to&amp;nbsp;skip&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was listening to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maximumfun.org/bullseye/judge-john-hodgman-episode-151-sic-semper-dramatis&#34;&gt;not-very-recent episode of &lt;em&gt;Judge John Hodgman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recently where Judge Hodgman, Bailiff Jesse, and an unspeakably fabulous man debated the equivalence of reading and listening to audiobooks, and ever since I&amp;#8217;ve been paying much more attention to the different dynamics of the experiences. Having just made it through Spring Break, and as a regular commuter, I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a lot of both, and my feeling&amp;#8212;somewhat surprisingly&amp;#8212;is that Judge Hodgman was right: they are &amp;#8220;separate but equal&amp;#8221; experiences. A book and its audiobook offer two fundamentally different ways to experience the story&amp;nbsp;they&amp;nbsp;describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the assumptions that I bring to gaming is that ultimately, games&amp;#8212;at least, the games that I like&amp;#8212;are about &lt;em&gt;stories,&lt;/em&gt; and that videogames are just another medium for telling stories. The nature of the medium affects how we tell and experience stories, and so stories told through videogames are different from stories told through books, movies, or &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; shows. But McLuhan&amp;#8217;s assertion that &amp;#8220;the medium is the message&amp;#8221; has become cliché at this point, and so I&amp;#8217;ll say it maybe a&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story is an independent thing. It lives out there in the world of ideas, no matter who is telling it or listening to it&amp;#8212;even if nobody is. Think of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_aristocrats&#34;&gt;The Aristocrats.&lt;/a&gt;, a joke that&amp;#8217;s been told millions of times by millions of people. Each time, the story is the same; each time, the story is totally different. Think of Harry Potter, and especially of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pottermore.com&#34;&gt;Pottermore&lt;/a&gt;. The book series is long over, but &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;J. K.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Rowling still has the ability, through &lt;em&gt;Pottermore,&lt;/em&gt; to add to and alter Harry Potter &lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Canon&#34;&gt;canon&lt;/a&gt;. The implication is that the story&amp;#8212;and the world of Harry Potter&amp;#8212;extends far beyond the books, and that Rowling has access to that story. The books&amp;#8212;like each telling of &lt;em&gt;The Aristocrats&lt;/em&gt; offer one glimpse into a platonic Story that extends beyond the limited bounds of the instance&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;telling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The medium in which a telling takes place, then, shapes how an audience can access that story, sometimes fundamentally. I remember re-watching &lt;em&gt;The Green Mile&lt;/em&gt; once and being very confused that a specific scene was missing. Eventually, I realized what had happened: having both read the book and seen the movie, my memory had populated a scene from the book with Tom Hanks and Michael Clarke Duncan, even though I&amp;#8217;d never actually seen them act out that scene. My viewing of the movie shaped my reading of the book, and my reading of the book shaped my viewing of the movie, because each shaped my experience of the story that both&amp;nbsp;were&amp;nbsp;telling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like books and films, books and audiobooks offer fundamentally different glimpses through the window of narrative at the Story they tell. Reading aloud is an act of interpreting, and sometimes those interpretive choices fundamentally change the nature of&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, &lt;em&gt;Let the Right One In.&lt;/em&gt; It includes the&amp;nbsp;following&amp;nbsp;dialog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Never again. No matter what&amp;nbsp;you&amp;nbsp;say.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Håkan…&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;No.&amp;nbsp;It&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;just&amp;#8212;no.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is, you&amp;#8217;ll note, no attribution in any of these lines, and the surrounding texts offers no descriptive detail of any kind. This scene is just dialog, just back-and-forth between the two participants. Håkan is named, but the other party is not. If I&amp;#8217;d come to the novel fresh&amp;#8212;that is, without having seen the film adaptation&amp;#8212;I would have no idea who Håkan was talking to. The sex, age, personality, and background of Håkan&amp;#8217;s interlocutor would have been completely blank for me, reading this text&amp;#8212;they would have been words coming from a void. And I presume that this is Lindqvist&amp;#8217;s intention in leaving out description and attribution: he &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; this person to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an audiobook, however, things become immediately more complicated. There&amp;#8217;s no clear way to punctuate, and so a reader-out-loud would immediately need to delineate in some way which lines belong to which speaker&amp;#8212;and also to clarify that the lines &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; coming from a speaker, and not the narrator. They would need to characterize the voices in some way. Håkan is easy&amp;#8212;we&amp;#8217;ve heard from him prior to this, and so presumably the reader would have already established a voice for him. We&amp;#8217;ve met the second speaker, too&amp;#8212;but in the context of the scene, we don&amp;#8217;t know who is speaking. So if you&amp;#8217;re reading this for an audiobook, you have to decide: do I use the voice associated with the speaker, since I know who is speaking? If so, you give away something that is intentionally ambiguous in the text; in fact, you give away a major plot point. If not, how do you voice this speaker? There is no such thing as a neutral voice, and even if there were, using a neutral voice for this speaker would imply that it&amp;#8217;s a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; character, not one we&amp;#8217;ve already met. This is even more complicated because to give a voice to that character, you&amp;#8217;ll have to make some concrete choices about how that character sounds&amp;#8212;and it&amp;#8217;s another major plot point that this character&amp;#8217;s appearance&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;deceiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example I&amp;#8217;ve been dealing with recently is Brandon Sanderson&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Mistborn&lt;/em&gt; series, which I&amp;#8217;m re-reading/re-listening-to. I&amp;#8217;m going back and forth between the written text and Michael Kramer&amp;#8217;s excellent reading (which complicates things further). The first time I experienced the last book, &lt;em&gt;The Hero of Ages,&lt;/em&gt; I was listening to it, and I realized immediately that Kramer was put in an impossible position with the very first words of the&amp;nbsp;first&amp;nbsp;chapter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am, unfortunately, the Hero&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;Ages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of who, precisely, the Hero of Ages was, is, or will be is one of the foundational questions of the series, and it is a question that is answered somewhere near the end of the final book. Almost every chapter of &lt;em&gt;The Hero of Ages&lt;/em&gt; begins with an epigraph taken from a text written after the events of the book by&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;Hero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is probably no spoiler to say that the Hero of Ages is revealed to be someone we already know, rather than a brand new character introduced in the last pages of the trilogy. The simple statement above is the epigraph for Chapter 1. Thus, before the story in which the Hero is revealed begins, Kramer has to read a statement of identity written by the Hero. And the Hero already has&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can Kramer do? If he reads it in the voice of the character who will be revealed to be the Hero, listeners who have been through the series in audio format&amp;#8212;as I had, when I first listened&amp;#8212;will likely know immediately who the Hero will be. If he reads it in a different voice, he steers us in the wrong direction&amp;#8212;which might, in fact, have been preferable. If he reads it in the narrator&amp;#8217;s voice&amp;#8212;as he does later with an epigraph from a different source, with a unknown writer&amp;#8212;it becomes unclear that what he is reading is an epigraph, and not a part of the story. Ultimately, he read the epigraph in the character&amp;#8217;s voice, and in that way gave a huge hint about the end of the book. I don&amp;#8217;t remember for sure if I guessed instantly who the Hero would be&amp;#8212;I think I did&amp;#8212;but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; remember hearing that first epigraph and immediately eliminating several characters&amp;#8212;including a few of my most&amp;nbsp;likely&amp;nbsp;guesses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make the book any less than what it was? I don&amp;#8217;t think so. It&amp;#8217;s a problem with no solution, and to my mind, it doesn&amp;#8217;t take anything away from my experience of the story. What it does do is add an intermediary between me and the story that didn&amp;#8217;t exist before, and the choices of that intermediary affect my experience of that story. Kramer becomes, almost, a second author, reshaping the way that I experience the story that&amp;nbsp;Sanderson&amp;nbsp;wrote. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very similar to the weird thing that will be happening with &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; in the coming seasons, as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2015/03/game-of-thrones-tv-show-will-spoil-books&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; show progresses beyond the realm of the books on which it&amp;#8217;s based&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;#8217;re both trying to tell the same story&amp;#8212;more or less&amp;#8212;and now we&amp;#8217;ve got two different windows onto that story. Are they the same? Definitely not. But we can&amp;#8217;t really call one of them the &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; story anymore, because now &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; is doing something &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than simply adapting &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;Fire.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate, but equal. Hodgman was, of&amp;nbsp;course,&amp;nbsp;right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Better sorting with Keyboard Maestro Macro Palettes</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://inthecourseofmyduties.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of student writing. I usually do this digitally, as my handwriting is so awful as to make doctors weep. And, because students in the same classes tend to be learning the same things at the same time, I often find myself needing to say the same thing over and over, to lots of students in lots of&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;classes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I need to be able to inject these comments quickly, easily, and repeatedly, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to find a good way to automate them for some time now. In my last attempt, I&amp;#8217;ve figured out a pretty good way to do this—solving a long-standing problem I&amp;#8217;ve had with Keyboard Maestro in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of quick examples. Some of these are usually marginal comments about&amp;nbsp;small&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college writing, it’s polite to refer to people we don’t know by their last name, rather than their first (so “Tan” rather&amp;nbsp;than&amp;nbsp;“Amy”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others are usually longer notes about more significant,&amp;nbsp;essay-level&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;linked-comment&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sentence Boundaries.&lt;/em&gt; We’ll talk about this in class a bit later, but for the moment, here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/598/1/&#34;&gt;a resource online&lt;/a&gt; for how to look at this issue. I’d definitely recommend you come work with me in my office on this&amp;#8212;it’s a tough thing to figure out, and it’s one that’s really important for&amp;nbsp;academic&amp;nbsp;readers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt&amp;nbsp;1:&amp;nbsp;Textexpander&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I need to drop these in at different times in different places and different formats, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to find a way to integrate them into my workflow that is both unobtrusive and pervasively accessible. At first, these were a series of &lt;a href=&#34;http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/index.html&#34;&gt;Textexpander&lt;/a&gt; snippets, but the problem with that—at least for me—is that I ended up with a slurry of arcane abbreviations that I could never remember, and so I ultimately forgot I&amp;#8217;d set them up. As a result, Textexpander flopped for this purpose&amp;nbsp;pretty&amp;nbsp;quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt 2: Keyboard Maestro&amp;nbsp;Macro&amp;nbsp;Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&#34;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; seemed a logical next step, especially when I realized that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/documentation/5/macrogroups.html&#34;&gt;Macro Group&lt;/a&gt; could be set to show a palette in response to a keystroke. So I set up a macro group to show a palette&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in response to &lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;, and I ended up with something like&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 2: One Big Keyboard Maestro Macro Group&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-2.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sorted and grouped comments in a way that made sense to me at the time, but as things were, I ended up with a couple of commonplaces that didn&amp;#8217;t quite fit well into an established category. It was also kind of difficult to sort through—I had a big long list of things, and no easy way to get to them. So the workflow for inserting a commonplace&amp;nbsp;comment&amp;nbsp;was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find desired comment among&amp;nbsp;enormous&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand to mouse&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;desired&amp;nbsp;comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand back&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is still faster than typing, for sure, but the two big irritations come in steps 3 and 4—first, finding the comment I want among this sorted, but still quite long, list, and second, having to take my hand away from the keyboard for a task that is,&amp;nbsp;essentially,&amp;nbsp;typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked for a long time, but when I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macdrifter.com/2012/10/so-you-need-an-app-launcher.html&#34;&gt;Gabe Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s post&lt;/a&gt; about using a macro group for dedicated application launchers, I started thinking about&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt 3: Dedicated&amp;nbsp;Macro&amp;nbsp;Groups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like about Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s method is that the revealed palette has hotkeys &lt;em&gt;for each entry,&lt;/em&gt; which my method didn&amp;#8217;t really allow. (I certainly &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have set up individual hotkeys for each entry, but I had way too many for that to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;practical.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really needed, though, was a &lt;em&gt;hierarchy&lt;/em&gt; of macros—a group of groups, in essence. Since Keyboard Maestro doesn&amp;#8217;t allow nesting macro groups in this way, I had to improvise. And because I&amp;#8217;m demanding and fiddly, I had to improvise&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3.1:&amp;nbsp;Group&amp;nbsp;Hotkeys&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the easy way to do things, the way that Keyboard Maestro is most comfortable with. I broke my commonplaces into categorized Macro Groups and gave each macro group a hotkey. (This is identical to&amp;nbsp;Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;setup.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 3.1: Look at them macro groups.&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.1-mgroups.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Style comments, I can simply hit &lt;code&gt;⌘^⌥F2&lt;/code&gt; and get a comment&amp;nbsp;palette.&amp;nbsp;Easy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 3.1: My MLA Style Comment Palette&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.1-mlapalette.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this leaves me with six different non-semantic keyboard shortcuts, with the possibility of expanding more or less infinitely as I add new categories and groupings. (In fact, even as I was typing the keyboard shortcut above, I got it wrong. I could try to sort out more meaningful shortcuts, but that&amp;#8217;d still require me getting all that stuff sorted out in my memory, which is unreliable&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;best.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would really be ideal is if I could get a macro palette that would allow me to choose from a number of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; palettes. This&amp;nbsp;seems&amp;nbsp;trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Attempt 3.2:&amp;nbsp;A&amp;nbsp;meta-group.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious way to approach this is to set up another macro group intended to launch the palettes for each individual&amp;nbsp;comment&amp;nbsp;group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My meta-group&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.2-metagroup.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious way to set up the macros is&amp;nbsp;like&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Send a keystroke! What could be easier!&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.2-bad-macro.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that this doesn&amp;#8217;t work. It seems that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; simulates the desired keystroke, but that the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; receive that simulated keystroke. 
In fact, there is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; straightforward way I&amp;#8217;ve found&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to have a Keyboard Maestro macro show a palette for another macro group for one action—which is exactly what I want, and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; what I want. &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; can &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; that, but the only ways it knows how is by a hotkey, the dropdown menu, or the intrusive (to me) global&amp;nbsp;macro&amp;nbsp;palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Current solution:&amp;nbsp;Abuse&amp;nbsp;Applescript!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out I was only one step removed from a solution. What I needed was for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to tell &lt;em&gt;something else&lt;/em&gt; to send the keystroke in question to the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine. Applescript is the easiest way to&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my&amp;nbsp;current&amp;nbsp;setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macros grouped as above, with arbitrary hotkeys.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Macros grouped as I desire&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-solution-macro-groups.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta-palette keyed to &lt;code&gt;^;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Meta-palette&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-solution-meta-palette.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palette launcher macros set up to run an Applescript like the following:&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codebox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;application&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;System Events&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;process&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Keyboard Maestro Engine&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;key code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;control&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;option&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;AppleScript&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ensures that the keystroke actually gets to the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine, and so this &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work to launch a palette for one action via another palette launched for&amp;nbsp;one&amp;nbsp;action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The&amp;nbsp;next&amp;nbsp;step&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When next I come back to fiddle with this setup, I think I&amp;#8217;ll be going back to Textexpander. &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is much better at dealing with text than &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and so when it comes to something like &lt;a href=&#34;#linked-comment&#34;&gt;the above&lt;/a&gt;, I could use a rich text snippet rather than a Markdown one when inserting a comment in Pages&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;Preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, I&amp;#8217;d still use the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; palette system I&amp;#8217;ve set up here to trigger the Textexpander snippets. I&amp;#8217;ll leave how to do that as an exercise to&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually isn&amp;#8217;t true. What I did initially is use a macro group wherein all of the macros had the same hotkey trigger (&lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;), so that hitting that key combo brought up a disambiguation palette. Different implementation, same effect.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have a screenshot of my actual setup when things were like this; this is a quick replication of what I had initially.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;vampiric hissing noises&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although of course that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean there isn&amp;#8217;t one; if there&amp;#8217;s a better way, please let me know.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I won&amp;#8217;t be using these hotkeys directly, I picked things that wouldn&amp;#8217;t compete with anything else on my system—in this case, &lt;code&gt;⌘⌥^F[1–6]&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;key code 120&lt;/code&gt; part is the integer version of the key code for, in this case, the F6 key. I got these using the Event Viewer included with &lt;a href=&#34;http://pqrs.org/macosx/keyremap4macbook/&#34;&gt;KeyRemap4MacBook&lt;/a&gt;, but this is necessary because the F keys seem to be a special case. Depending on the key, there may be a simpler way to do it: the System Events dictionary also includes the simpler &amp;#8220;keystroke&amp;#8221; command that allows the use of simple strings, so an Applescript to trigger my meta-palette could simply use &lt;code&gt;keystroke &#34;;&#34; using control down&lt;/code&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 6 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">*Assassin's Creed's* Identity Crisis</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Spoiler&amp;nbsp;Alert&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following contains plot spoilers for &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed: Revelations.&lt;/em&gt; But inasmuch as the revealed details are pretty much ridiculous, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;worry&amp;nbsp;too&amp;nbsp;much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iteration is important. One of the most elegant things about the difference between, say, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 2&lt;/em&gt; is the way in which the combat system builds on what has come before. On the one hand, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; feels like &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; On the other, it&amp;#8217;s streamlined. Simpler. More elegant. And what speaks most highly for it, I think, is that I feel like playing &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; made me better understand what combat in &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I recognize that games that come in series are &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to iterate. But having just finished &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed: Revelations,&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;m starting to remember the &lt;em&gt;dangers&lt;/em&gt; of iteration.
One of my greater frustrations is the fact that &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:R&lt;/em&gt; seems pretty severely unaware of what it actually &lt;em&gt;is.&lt;/em&gt; I remember, when I first started playing the original &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; being somewhat flummoxed by the appearance of Desmond, a distinctly modern and eminently clueless apparent post-skater hobo trapped in some sort of oddjob research facility. This was, I had been assured, a game about assassins, and particularly Crusades-era assassins wandering about the Holy Land. Not a game about hominid lab-rats whose greatest in-game accomplishment was going&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;ve bought into it, and happily: the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; series is &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; Desmond, not about Altaïr or Ezio. And, to my mind, from the moment that Desmond &lt;em&gt;et. al.&lt;/em&gt; bust out of the Templaricorps Ltd&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; research facility, the entire series begins building toward a very specific moment: the moment when Desmond must take the (perpetually hazy) mission of the Assassin Order into his own unemployed and mostly unskilled hands. This is really the promise of the whole series:&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that someday, all this time playing video games will pay off for Desmond, and he will suddenly &lt;em&gt;actually be an assassin.&lt;/em&gt; Desmond, paying homage to the garb of his ancestors with his dirty Wal-Mart hoodie, will take the fight which I can&amp;#8217;t remember what we&amp;#8217;re fighting about to the Templars, because at least I remember that they&amp;#8217;re the&amp;nbsp;bad&amp;nbsp;guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so these are the things I have been waiting for, since that moment at the tail of&amp;nbsp;game&amp;nbsp;1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Desmond will display genuine assassin-fu in the&amp;nbsp;real&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That he will use this ability to kick some&amp;nbsp;Templar&amp;nbsp;ass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not too much&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead, I feel like the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; games are working through a very&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;progression: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desmond&amp;#8217;s ancestors use increasingly anachronistic tools to play increasingly&amp;nbsp;absurd&amp;nbsp;minigames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desmond is driven around unconscious in a series&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;trucks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s like Desmond, shiftless roustabout that he is, can&amp;#8217;t even be bothered to stay awake through his whirlwind tour of Europe and the Holy Land. His only achievement to speak of, in one of those exceedingly rare bouts of wakefulness, is accidentally murdering his closest ally.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in the increasingly implausible landscape of his genetic&amp;nbsp;memory,&amp;nbsp;Ezio: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goes on a scavenger hunt&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;masquerades as a&amp;nbsp;punk-rock&amp;nbsp;lutist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is dragged behind a speeding wagon, Indiana&amp;nbsp;Jones&amp;nbsp;style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completes innumerable tasks centered around improvised (and completely impractical) explosives, such as a bomb you can stick to someone&amp;#8217;s face such that their head explodes in a shower of fake gold coins, and to which they respond not by being concerned about the bomb but by being excited about&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;coins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wanders haphazardly through the memories of Altaïr, including conducting a couple of escort missions despite the fact that he is &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NINETY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;YEARS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OLD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coordinates a series of tower-defense style excursions where we learn that the Templars have cannons, ballistae, and machine guns which they will &lt;em&gt;only use in this context&lt;/em&gt; for reasons&amp;nbsp;completely&amp;nbsp;unclear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defeats the heir to the Sultanate of the Ottoman Empire &lt;strong&gt;by accidentally inventing parasailing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; somewhat in spite of myself. But at this point, while what I should be expecting is a conclusion, I feel like I have &lt;em&gt;no idea&lt;/em&gt; what the next set of wild-eyed iterations will bring. Given the weird, persistent appearance of Greek deities and the increasingly elaborate killing methods, I&amp;#8217;m starting to suspect that we&amp;#8217;ll find out soon that the whole &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed&lt;/em&gt; series is actually an extremely elaborate prequel to &lt;em&gt;God of War.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay so that&amp;#8217;s not the real name of the company, but it may as well have been.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, we hope, for us.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, if I may say, is also really the only thing resembling voice talent on the cast, although this may change  with the apparent addition of John de Lancie to the cast.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a thing that happens: while you are parasailing on the road from Constantinople to Masyaf, in order to protect your unconscionably forgiving girlfriend from an unlimited stream of Templar guards, you dip magnificently out of the sky to grab a guard off his moving horse, whereupon you hurl said guard forward&amp;#8212;accelerating him, to my estimation, about another 15-20 mph&amp;#8212;such that he knocks &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; guard off &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; moving horse. (Your girlfriend, despite not knowing that you are an assassin, is &lt;em&gt;totally fine with this.&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which, come to think of it, might actually be kind of cool.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Things I Suck At</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/things-i-suck-at"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/things-i-suck-at</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;/categories/geek&#34;&gt;fiddle around with a lot of things.&lt;/a&gt;  It&amp;#8217;s in my nature. I began listing my recent forays into configuring email as an example, and I realized quite quickly that the odyssey ought to be its own post. The reason I do this sort of fiddling, though, almost always composed of two intertwining&amp;nbsp;mental&amp;nbsp;phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know what I&amp;nbsp;need,&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know the limitations of the thing I&amp;#8217;m&amp;nbsp;fiddling&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when we&amp;#8217;re talking about software or something similar, I know up front what the limitations are; often, though, I only find out by playing around with it. Likewise, I often know what I need up front; other times, though, I only find out what I need by finding out where my needs rub up against the limitations of whatever it is I&amp;#8217;m trying to&amp;nbsp;work&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w/71&#34;&gt;Back to Work 71&lt;/a&gt;, I started thinking about the problems that exist in organizations&amp;#8212;things like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://passiveaggressivenotes.com/&#34;&gt;passive aggression&lt;/a&gt; that Merlin and Dan were discussing&amp;#8212;as functions of that same pair of forces. More specifically, it made me think about the problems I have as a teacher with my students, the problems my students have with me as a teacher, and perhaps most importantly, the problems I have with myself as a teacher.  &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;All these problems&amp;#8212;and perhaps all problems&amp;#8212;come down to a conflict between one party&amp;#8217;s expectations and another&amp;nbsp;party&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;limitations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point&amp;#8212;and at that absurdly high level of abstraction&amp;#8212;there are two ways to go about resolving&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise the&amp;nbsp;expectation,&amp;nbsp;or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolve&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;limitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What occurred to me as I was listening is that in the same way that what David Allen calls the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikisummaries.org/Getting_Things_Done:_The_Art_of_Stress-Free_Productivity#Chapter_9_--_Doing:_Making_the_Best_Action_Choices&#34;&gt;10,000 foot perspective&lt;/a&gt; is important to understanding the everyday projects and actions we undertake, &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;understanding my own limitations on a broad scale can, I think, help me avoid the problems I tend to face in the classroom (and, I&amp;nbsp;suspect,&amp;nbsp;beyond).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus: &lt;a href=&#34;/things-i-suck-at&#34;&gt;Things I Suck At&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembering.&lt;/em&gt; Really: I don&amp;#8217;t remember &lt;em&gt;anything.&lt;/em&gt; If you talked to me about it half an hour ago, there&amp;#8217;s a decent chance I&amp;#8217;ve already forgotten it. I don&amp;#8217;t mean to; it&amp;#8217;s just the truth of me. If you need me to remember something, or to do something for you, &lt;em&gt;email me.&lt;/em&gt; Just talking to me will do pretty much&amp;nbsp;no&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Planning ahead.&lt;/em&gt; I am writing this on July 11, 2012, and by my standards, that&amp;#8217;s an &lt;em&gt;absurd&lt;/em&gt; amount of foresight for a Fall semester. Whether with my classes or with my life, I am generally no good at planning ahead. Sometimes this is because I&amp;#8217;ve let time get away from me (see below), but a lot of the time&amp;#8212;at least in the context of my classes&amp;#8212;it&amp;#8217;s because what I&amp;#8217;m doing on any given day is determined by what&amp;#8217;s happened in class in the&amp;nbsp;days&amp;nbsp;before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot for anyone more future-oriented than myself, though, is that if you ask me a question like &amp;#8220;What are we doing in class next Friday,&amp;#8221; I probably can&amp;#8217;t answer, because it likely depends rather a lot on what happens in class&amp;nbsp;next&amp;nbsp;Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estimating time.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; do I suck at this. I suck at this &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning my wife and I were talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ravelry.com/jobs&#34;&gt;a job posting&lt;/a&gt; that the reliably awesome folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ravelry.com/&#34;&gt;Ravelry&lt;/a&gt; have posted, and I said, &amp;#8220;I kinda want to apply&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;that.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;You can&amp;#8217;t,&amp;#8221; she said. &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s a full time job.&amp;#8221; (I already have a full time job,&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t do it full time, sure, but maybe I could do it full time during the Summer, and half time during the&amp;nbsp;school&amp;nbsp;year.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Do you think you have twenty extra hours a week during&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;semester?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, until she said it like that, I did. I&amp;#8217;m just &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; both at judging how long things will take and at judging how much time I have to&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;the.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, in class, I try never to say things like &amp;#8220;I will have X ready by Y,&amp;#8221; because one or both of those problems will likely make me wrong. I will usually say &amp;#8220;I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have X by Y,&amp;#8221; which leaves me a little room to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tackling things piecemeal.&lt;/em&gt; Let&amp;#8217;s say today is Monday, and I have 50 student papers that were just turned in, and I want them to be back in student hands by Friday. What a normal person would do is try to tackle 10 papers a day, so that by the end of the day Friday, they&amp;#8217;re done.&amp;nbsp;Yay!&amp;nbsp;Reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will probably not do this. Instead, I will try to orchestrate things so that I have an enormous block of time so that I can do them all at once. This may or may not work, and because it&amp;#8217;s harder to get ten hours or so at a block than it is to get two hours together five times, it&amp;#8217;ll likely end up meaning that I don&amp;#8217;t accomplish things according to my&amp;nbsp;own&amp;nbsp;deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prioritizing.&lt;/em&gt; Broadly speaking, I have no idea what is important and what is not. If I have five tasks I need to complete, I have a lot of trouble deciding which I should approach first, even if one of them is &amp;#8220;exit the burning building.&amp;#8221;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being mean.&lt;/em&gt; This is a tough one. As a teacher, sometimes it&amp;#8217;s my job to be mean. I&amp;#8217;m good at that when it matters. If you need to fail my class, you need to fail my class&amp;#8212;and while that sucks for everybody, you&amp;#8217;re not going to be able to sweet-talk me out&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The times when I suck at being mean, though, are the little times. I set out my policies pretty clearly on my Syllabi, and I hold to those policies pretty clearly. So when someone comes to me and says, for example, &amp;#8220;I need to leave 45 minutes early today,&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;ll likely say &amp;#8220;Okay,&amp;#8221; and&amp;nbsp;mean&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, though, is that what the student hears is something like, &amp;#8220;Oh, of course visiting your out-of-state stylist for an elaborate purple up-do is more important than my class; by all means, come and go as you please and expect no consequences whatsoever.!&amp;#8221; When what I mean is &amp;#8220;Okay, that&amp;#8217;s your choice; as per the Syllabus, I&amp;#8217;ll be marking you&amp;nbsp;absent.&amp;nbsp;Ta!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention is to both include this on my Syllabi next semester&amp;#8212;or at least, include a link to the relevant page&amp;#8212;and to use this list to help me design my courses, such that I can build my practices and policies &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; my limitations, with the hope that I can thereby&amp;nbsp;avoid&amp;nbsp;problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll see how&amp;nbsp;it&amp;nbsp;goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in terms of its role on my Syllabus and its role in my life, I recognize that this should probably be paired with a corresponding list of Things I&amp;#8217;m Pretty Good At, but at the moment, I&amp;#8217;m wanting to work on some of those limitations, so this is coming first.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>