<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        Geek About Town - Full Posts    </title>
        <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2015-04-09T13:30:01Z</updated>

    <id>/blog/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">Audiobooks and the Platonic Story</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Spoiler&amp;nbsp;Alert&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following contains minor plot spoilers for John Ajvide Lindqvist&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Let the Right One In&lt;/em&gt; and Brandon Sanderson&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Mistborn&lt;/em&gt; trilogy. I&amp;#8217;ve veiled the details as much as possible, but if you&amp;#8217;re wanting to remain pristine, you might want to&amp;nbsp;skip&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was listening to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maximumfun.org/bullseye/judge-john-hodgman-episode-151-sic-semper-dramatis&#34;&gt;not-very-recent episode of &lt;em&gt;Judge John Hodgman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recently where Judge Hodgman, Bailiff Jesse, and an unspeakably fabulous man debated the equivalence of reading and listening to audiobooks, and ever since I&amp;#8217;ve been paying much more attention to the different dynamics of the experiences. Having just made it through Spring Break, and as a regular commuter, I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a lot of both, and my feeling&amp;#8212;somewhat surprisingly&amp;#8212;is that Judge Hodgman was right: they are &amp;#8220;separate but equal&amp;#8221; experiences. A book and its audiobook offer two fundamentally different ways to experience the story&amp;nbsp;they&amp;nbsp;describe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the assumptions that I bring to gaming is that ultimately, games&amp;#8212;at least, the games that I like&amp;#8212;are about &lt;em&gt;stories,&lt;/em&gt; and that videogames are just another medium for telling stories. The nature of the medium affects how we tell and experience stories, and so stories told through videogames are different from stories told through books, movies, or &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; shows. But McLuhan&amp;#8217;s assertion that &amp;#8220;the medium is the message&amp;#8221; has become cliché at this point, and so I&amp;#8217;ll say it maybe a&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A story is an independent thing. It lives out there in the world of ideas, no matter who is telling it or listening to it&amp;#8212;even if nobody is. Think of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_aristocrats&#34;&gt;The Aristocrats.&lt;/a&gt;, a joke that&amp;#8217;s been told millions of times by millions of people. Each time, the story is the same; each time, the story is totally different. Think of Harry Potter, and especially of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pottermore.com&#34;&gt;Pottermore&lt;/a&gt;. The book series is long over, but &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;J. K.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Rowling still has the ability, through &lt;em&gt;Pottermore,&lt;/em&gt; to add to and alter Harry Potter &lt;a href=&#34;http://harrypotter.wikia.com/wiki/Canon&#34;&gt;canon&lt;/a&gt;. The implication is that the story&amp;#8212;and the world of Harry Potter&amp;#8212;extends far beyond the books, and that Rowling has access to that story. The books&amp;#8212;like each telling of &lt;em&gt;The Aristocrats&lt;/em&gt; offer one glimpse into a platonic Story that extends beyond the limited bounds of the instance&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;telling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The medium in which a telling takes place, then, shapes how an audience can access that story, sometimes fundamentally. I remember re-watching &lt;em&gt;The Green Mile&lt;/em&gt; once and being very confused that a specific scene was missing. Eventually, I realized what had happened: having both read the book and seen the movie, my memory had populated a scene from the book with Tom Hanks and Michael Clarke Duncan, even though I&amp;#8217;d never actually seen them act out that scene. My viewing of the movie shaped my reading of the book, and my reading of the book shaped my viewing of the movie, because each shaped my experience of the story that both&amp;nbsp;were&amp;nbsp;telling. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like books and films, books and audiobooks offer fundamentally different glimpses through the window of narrative at the Story they tell. Reading aloud is an act of interpreting, and sometimes those interpretive choices fundamentally change the nature of&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;story. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, &lt;em&gt;Let the Right One In.&lt;/em&gt; It includes the&amp;nbsp;following&amp;nbsp;dialog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Never again. No matter what&amp;nbsp;you&amp;nbsp;say.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Håkan…&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;No.&amp;nbsp;It&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;just&amp;#8212;no.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is, you&amp;#8217;ll note, no attribution in any of these lines, and the surrounding texts offers no descriptive detail of any kind. This scene is just dialog, just back-and-forth between the two participants. Håkan is named, but the other party is not. If I&amp;#8217;d come to the novel fresh&amp;#8212;that is, without having seen the film adaptation&amp;#8212;I would have no idea who Håkan was talking to. The sex, age, personality, and background of Håkan&amp;#8217;s interlocutor would have been completely blank for me, reading this text&amp;#8212;they would have been words coming from a void. And I presume that this is Lindqvist&amp;#8217;s intention in leaving out description and attribution: he &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; this person to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an audiobook, however, things become immediately more complicated. There&amp;#8217;s no clear way to punctuate, and so a reader-out-loud would immediately need to delineate in some way which lines belong to which speaker&amp;#8212;and also to clarify that the lines &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; coming from a speaker, and not the narrator. They would need to characterize the voices in some way. Håkan is easy&amp;#8212;we&amp;#8217;ve heard from him prior to this, and so presumably the reader would have already established a voice for him. We&amp;#8217;ve met the second speaker, too&amp;#8212;but in the context of the scene, we don&amp;#8217;t know who is speaking. So if you&amp;#8217;re reading this for an audiobook, you have to decide: do I use the voice associated with the speaker, since I know who is speaking? If so, you give away something that is intentionally ambiguous in the text; in fact, you give away a major plot point. If not, how do you voice this speaker? There is no such thing as a neutral voice, and even if there were, using a neutral voice for this speaker would imply that it&amp;#8217;s a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; character, not one we&amp;#8217;ve already met. This is even more complicated because to give a voice to that character, you&amp;#8217;ll have to make some concrete choices about how that character sounds&amp;#8212;and it&amp;#8217;s another major plot point that this character&amp;#8217;s appearance&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;deceiving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another example I&amp;#8217;ve been dealing with recently is Brandon Sanderson&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;Mistborn&lt;/em&gt; series, which I&amp;#8217;m re-reading/re-listening-to. I&amp;#8217;m going back and forth between the written text and Michael Kramer&amp;#8217;s excellent reading (which complicates things further). The first time I experienced the last book, &lt;em&gt;The Hero of Ages,&lt;/em&gt; I was listening to it, and I realized immediately that Kramer was put in an impossible position with the very first words of the&amp;nbsp;first&amp;nbsp;chapter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am, unfortunately, the Hero&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;Ages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question of who, precisely, the Hero of Ages was, is, or will be is one of the foundational questions of the series, and it is a question that is answered somewhere near the end of the final book. Almost every chapter of &lt;em&gt;The Hero of Ages&lt;/em&gt; begins with an epigraph taken from a text written after the events of the book by&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;Hero. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is probably no spoiler to say that the Hero of Ages is revealed to be someone we already know, rather than a brand new character introduced in the last pages of the trilogy. The simple statement above is the epigraph for Chapter 1. Thus, before the story in which the Hero is revealed begins, Kramer has to read a statement of identity written by the Hero. And the Hero already has&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what can Kramer do? If he reads it in the voice of the character who will be revealed to be the Hero, listeners who have been through the series in audio format&amp;#8212;as I had, when I first listened&amp;#8212;will likely know immediately who the Hero will be. If he reads it in a different voice, he steers us in the wrong direction&amp;#8212;which might, in fact, have been preferable. If he reads it in the narrator&amp;#8217;s voice&amp;#8212;as he does later with an epigraph from a different source, with a unknown writer&amp;#8212;it becomes unclear that what he is reading is an epigraph, and not a part of the story. Ultimately, he read the epigraph in the character&amp;#8217;s voice, and in that way gave a huge hint about the end of the book. I don&amp;#8217;t remember for sure if I guessed instantly who the Hero would be&amp;#8212;I think I did&amp;#8212;but I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; remember hearing that first epigraph and immediately eliminating several characters&amp;#8212;including a few of my most&amp;nbsp;likely&amp;nbsp;guesses. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this make the book any less than what it was? I don&amp;#8217;t think so. It&amp;#8217;s a problem with no solution, and to my mind, it doesn&amp;#8217;t take anything away from my experience of the story. What it does do is add an intermediary between me and the story that didn&amp;#8217;t exist before, and the choices of that intermediary affect my experience of that story. Kramer becomes, almost, a second author, reshaping the way that I experience the story that&amp;nbsp;Sanderson&amp;nbsp;wrote. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is very similar to the weird thing that will be happening with &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; in the coming seasons, as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vanityfair.com/hollywood/2015/03/game-of-thrones-tv-show-will-spoil-books&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TV&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; show progresses beyond the realm of the books on which it&amp;#8217;s based&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;#8217;re both trying to tell the same story&amp;#8212;more or less&amp;#8212;and now we&amp;#8217;ve got two different windows onto that story. Are they the same? Definitely not. But we can&amp;#8217;t really call one of them the &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; story anymore, because now &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; is doing something &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; than simply adapting &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;Fire.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Separate, but equal. Hodgman was, of&amp;nbsp;course,&amp;nbsp;right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Better sorting with Keyboard Maestro Macro Palettes</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://inthecourseofmyduties.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of student writing. I usually do this digitally, as my handwriting is so awful as to make doctors weep. And, because students in the same classes tend to be learning the same things at the same time, I often find myself needing to say the same thing over and over, to lots of students in lots of&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;classes. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I need to be able to inject these comments quickly, easily, and repeatedly, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to find a good way to automate them for some time now. In my last attempt, I&amp;#8217;ve figured out a pretty good way to do this—solving a long-standing problem I&amp;#8217;ve had with Keyboard Maestro in&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of quick examples. Some of these are usually marginal comments about&amp;nbsp;small&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college writing, it’s polite to refer to people we don’t know by their last name, rather than their first (so “Tan” rather&amp;nbsp;than&amp;nbsp;“Amy”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others are usually longer notes about more significant,&amp;nbsp;essay-level&amp;nbsp;issues:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id=&#34;linked-comment&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sentence Boundaries.&lt;/em&gt; We’ll talk about this in class a bit later, but for the moment, here’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://owl.english.purdue.edu/owl/resource/598/1/&#34;&gt;a resource online&lt;/a&gt; for how to look at this issue. I’d definitely recommend you come work with me in my office on this&amp;#8212;it’s a tough thing to figure out, and it’s one that’s really important for&amp;nbsp;academic&amp;nbsp;readers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt&amp;nbsp;1:&amp;nbsp;Textexpander&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I need to drop these in at different times in different places and different formats, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to find a way to integrate them into my workflow that is both unobtrusive and pervasively accessible. At first, these were a series of &lt;a href=&#34;http://smilesoftware.com/TextExpander/index.html&#34;&gt;Textexpander&lt;/a&gt; snippets, but the problem with that—at least for me—is that I ended up with a slurry of arcane abbreviations that I could never remember, and so I ultimately forgot I&amp;#8217;d set them up. As a result, Textexpander flopped for this purpose&amp;nbsp;pretty&amp;nbsp;quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt 2: Keyboard Maestro&amp;nbsp;Macro&amp;nbsp;Group&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/main/&#34;&gt;Keyboard Maestro&lt;/a&gt; seemed a logical next step, especially when I realized that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.keyboardmaestro.com/documentation/5/macrogroups.html&#34;&gt;Macro Group&lt;/a&gt; could be set to show a palette in response to a keystroke. So I set up a macro group to show a palette&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in response to &lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;, and I ended up with something like&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 2: One Big Keyboard Maestro Macro Group&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-2.png&#34; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sorted and grouped comments in a way that made sense to me at the time, but as things were, I ended up with a couple of commonplaces that didn&amp;#8217;t quite fit well into an established category. It was also kind of difficult to sort through—I had a big long list of things, and no easy way to get to them. So the workflow for inserting a commonplace&amp;nbsp;comment&amp;nbsp;was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;palette&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find desired comment among&amp;nbsp;enormous&amp;nbsp;list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand to mouse&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Click&amp;nbsp;desired&amp;nbsp;comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hand back&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;keyboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is still faster than typing, for sure, but the two big irritations come in steps 3 and 4—first, finding the comment I want among this sorted, but still quite long, list, and second, having to take my hand away from the keyboard for a task that is,&amp;nbsp;essentially,&amp;nbsp;typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked for a long time, but when I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macdrifter.com/2012/10/so-you-need-an-app-launcher.html&#34;&gt;Gabe Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s post&lt;/a&gt; about using a macro group for dedicated application launchers, I started thinking about&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Attempt 3: Dedicated&amp;nbsp;Macro&amp;nbsp;Groups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like about Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s method is that the revealed palette has hotkeys &lt;em&gt;for each entry,&lt;/em&gt; which my method didn&amp;#8217;t really allow. (I certainly &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have set up individual hotkeys for each entry, but I had way too many for that to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;practical.) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I really needed, though, was a &lt;em&gt;hierarchy&lt;/em&gt; of macros—a group of groups, in essence. Since Keyboard Maestro doesn&amp;#8217;t allow nesting macro groups in this way, I had to improvise. And because I&amp;#8217;m demanding and fiddly, I had to improvise&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3.1:&amp;nbsp;Group&amp;nbsp;Hotkeys&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the easy way to do things, the way that Keyboard Maestro is most comfortable with. I broke my commonplaces into categorized Macro Groups and gave each macro group a hotkey. (This is identical to&amp;nbsp;Weatherhead&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;setup.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 3.1: Look at them macro groups.&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.1-mgroups.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MLA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Style comments, I can simply hit &lt;code&gt;⌘^⌥F2&lt;/code&gt; and get a comment&amp;nbsp;palette.&amp;nbsp;Easy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Attempt 3.1: My MLA Style Comment Palette&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.1-mlapalette.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this leaves me with six different non-semantic keyboard shortcuts, with the possibility of expanding more or less infinitely as I add new categories and groupings. (In fact, even as I was typing the keyboard shortcut above, I got it wrong. I could try to sort out more meaningful shortcuts, but that&amp;#8217;d still require me getting all that stuff sorted out in my memory, which is unreliable&amp;nbsp;at&amp;nbsp;best.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would really be ideal is if I could get a macro palette that would allow me to choose from a number of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; palettes. This&amp;nbsp;seems&amp;nbsp;trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Attempt 3.2:&amp;nbsp;A&amp;nbsp;meta-group.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious way to approach this is to set up another macro group intended to launch the palettes for each individual&amp;nbsp;comment&amp;nbsp;group. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My meta-group&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.2-metagroup.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The obvious way to set up the macros is&amp;nbsp;like&amp;nbsp;this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Send a keystroke! What could be easier!&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-attempt-3.2-bad-macro.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that this doesn&amp;#8217;t work. It seems that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; simulates the desired keystroke, but that the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; receive that simulated keystroke. 
In fact, there is &lt;em&gt;no&lt;/em&gt; straightforward way I&amp;#8217;ve found&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to have a Keyboard Maestro macro show a palette for another macro group for one action—which is exactly what I want, and &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; what I want. &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; can &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; that, but the only ways it knows how is by a hotkey, the dropdown menu, or the intrusive (to me) global&amp;nbsp;macro&amp;nbsp;palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Current solution:&amp;nbsp;Abuse&amp;nbsp;Applescript!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out I was only one step removed from a solution. What I needed was for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to tell &lt;em&gt;something else&lt;/em&gt; to send the keystroke in question to the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine. Applescript is the easiest way to&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my&amp;nbsp;current&amp;nbsp;setup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macros grouped as above, with arbitrary hotkeys.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Macros grouped as I desire&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-solution-macro-groups.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta-palette keyed to &lt;code&gt;^;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Meta-palette&#34; src=&#34;/media/images/posts/2012-10-12-solution-meta-palette.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Palette launcher macros set up to run an Applescript like the following:&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;codebox&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;code&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;application&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;System Events&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;process&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;quot;Keyboard Maestro Engine&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;key code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;mi&#34;&gt;120&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;command&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;control&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;option&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;down&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;tell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;AppleScript&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This ensures that the keystroke actually gets to the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; engine, and so this &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; work to launch a palette for one action via another palette launched for&amp;nbsp;one&amp;nbsp;action. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The&amp;nbsp;next&amp;nbsp;step&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When next I come back to fiddle with this setup, I think I&amp;#8217;ll be going back to Textexpander. &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;TE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is much better at dealing with text than &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, and so when it comes to something like &lt;a href=&#34;#linked-comment&#34;&gt;the above&lt;/a&gt;, I could use a rich text snippet rather than a Markdown one when inserting a comment in Pages&amp;nbsp;or&amp;nbsp;Preview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that case, I&amp;#8217;d still use the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; palette system I&amp;#8217;ve set up here to trigger the Textexpander snippets. I&amp;#8217;ll leave how to do that as an exercise to&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This actually isn&amp;#8217;t true. What I did initially is use a macro group wherein all of the macros had the same hotkey trigger (&lt;code&gt;⌘⌥T&lt;/code&gt;), so that hitting that key combo brought up a disambiguation palette. Different implementation, same effect.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t have a screenshot of my actual setup when things were like this; this is a quick replication of what I had initially.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;vampiric hissing noises&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although of course that doesn&amp;#8217;t mean there isn&amp;#8217;t one; if there&amp;#8217;s a better way, please let me know.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I won&amp;#8217;t be using these hotkeys directly, I picked things that wouldn&amp;#8217;t compete with anything else on my system—in this case, &lt;code&gt;⌘⌥^F[1–6]&lt;/code&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;key code 120&lt;/code&gt; part is the integer version of the key code for, in this case, the F6 key. I got these using the Event Viewer included with &lt;a href=&#34;http://pqrs.org/macosx/keyremap4macbook/&#34;&gt;KeyRemap4MacBook&lt;/a&gt;, but this is necessary because the F keys seem to be a special case. Depending on the key, there may be a simpler way to do it: the System Events dictionary also includes the simpler &amp;#8220;keystroke&amp;#8221; command that allows the use of simple strings, so an Applescript to trigger my meta-palette could simply use &lt;code&gt;keystroke &#34;;&#34; using control down&lt;/code&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 6 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">*Assassin's Creed's* Identity Crisis</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;section class=&#39;spoiler&#39;&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Spoiler&amp;nbsp;Alert&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The following contains plot spoilers for &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed: Revelations.&lt;/em&gt; But inasmuch as the revealed details are pretty much ridiculous, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t&amp;nbsp;worry&amp;nbsp;too&amp;nbsp;much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iteration is important. One of the most elegant things about the difference between, say, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 2&lt;/em&gt; is the way in which the combat system builds on what has come before. On the one hand, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; feels like &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; On the other, it&amp;#8217;s streamlined. Simpler. More elegant. And what speaks most highly for it, I think, is that I feel like playing &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; made me better understand what combat in &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I recognize that games that come in series are &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to iterate. But having just finished &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed: Revelations,&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;m starting to remember the &lt;em&gt;dangers&lt;/em&gt; of iteration.
One of my greater frustrations is the fact that &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:R&lt;/em&gt; seems pretty severely unaware of what it actually &lt;em&gt;is.&lt;/em&gt; I remember, when I first started playing the original &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; being somewhat flummoxed by the appearance of Desmond, a distinctly modern and eminently clueless apparent post-skater hobo trapped in some sort of oddjob research facility. This was, I had been assured, a game about assassins, and particularly Crusades-era assassins wandering about the Holy Land. Not a game about hominid lab-rats whose greatest in-game accomplishment was going&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;#8217;ve bought into it, and happily: the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; series is &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; Desmond, not about Altaïr or Ezio. And, to my mind, from the moment that Desmond &lt;em&gt;et. al.&lt;/em&gt; bust out of the Templaricorps Ltd&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; research facility, the entire series begins building toward a very specific moment: the moment when Desmond must take the (perpetually hazy) mission of the Assassin Order into his own unemployed and mostly unskilled hands. This is really the promise of the whole series:&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; that someday, all this time playing video games will pay off for Desmond, and he will suddenly &lt;em&gt;actually be an assassin.&lt;/em&gt; Desmond, paying homage to the garb of his ancestors with his dirty Wal-Mart hoodie, will take the fight which I can&amp;#8217;t remember what we&amp;#8217;re fighting about to the Templars, because at least I remember that they&amp;#8217;re the&amp;nbsp;bad&amp;nbsp;guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so these are the things I have been waiting for, since that moment at the tail of&amp;nbsp;game&amp;nbsp;1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That Desmond will display genuine assassin-fu in the&amp;nbsp;real&amp;nbsp;world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That he will use this ability to kick some&amp;nbsp;Templar&amp;nbsp;ass.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not too much&amp;nbsp;to&amp;nbsp;ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But instead, I feel like the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; games are working through a very&amp;nbsp;different&amp;nbsp;progression: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desmond&amp;#8217;s ancestors use increasingly anachronistic tools to play increasingly&amp;nbsp;absurd&amp;nbsp;minigames.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Desmond is driven around unconscious in a series&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;trucks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s like Desmond, shiftless roustabout that he is, can&amp;#8217;t even be bothered to stay awake through his whirlwind tour of Europe and the Holy Land. His only achievement to speak of, in one of those exceedingly rare bouts of wakefulness, is accidentally murdering his closest ally.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in the increasingly implausible landscape of his genetic&amp;nbsp;memory,&amp;nbsp;Ezio: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;goes on a scavenger hunt&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;masquerades as a&amp;nbsp;punk-rock&amp;nbsp;lutist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is dragged behind a speeding wagon, Indiana&amp;nbsp;Jones&amp;nbsp;style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;completes innumerable tasks centered around improvised (and completely impractical) explosives, such as a bomb you can stick to someone&amp;#8217;s face such that their head explodes in a shower of fake gold coins, and to which they respond not by being concerned about the bomb but by being excited about&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;coins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wanders haphazardly through the memories of Altaïr, including conducting a couple of escort missions despite the fact that he is &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;NINETY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;YEARS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OLD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;coordinates a series of tower-defense style excursions where we learn that the Templars have cannons, ballistae, and machine guns which they will &lt;em&gt;only use in this context&lt;/em&gt; for reasons&amp;nbsp;completely&amp;nbsp;unclear.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;defeats the heir to the Sultanate of the Ottoman Empire &lt;strong&gt;by accidentally inventing parasailing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m looking forward to &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;AC3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; somewhat in spite of myself. But at this point, while what I should be expecting is a conclusion, I feel like I have &lt;em&gt;no idea&lt;/em&gt; what the next set of wild-eyed iterations will bring. Given the weird, persistent appearance of Greek deities and the increasingly elaborate killing methods, I&amp;#8217;m starting to suspect that we&amp;#8217;ll find out soon that the whole &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed&lt;/em&gt; series is actually an extremely elaborate prequel to &lt;em&gt;God of War.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay so that&amp;#8217;s not the real name of the company, but it may as well have been.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, we hope, for us.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who, if I may say, is also really the only thing resembling voice talent on the cast, although this may change  with the apparent addition of John de Lancie to the cast.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a thing that happens: while you are parasailing on the road from Constantinople to Masyaf, in order to protect your unconscionably forgiving girlfriend from an unlimited stream of Templar guards, you dip magnificently out of the sky to grab a guard off his moving horse, whereupon you hurl said guard forward&amp;#8212;accelerating him, to my estimation, about another 15-20 mph&amp;#8212;such that he knocks &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; guard off &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; moving horse. (Your girlfriend, despite not knowing that you are an assassin, is &lt;em&gt;totally fine with this.&lt;/em&gt;)&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which, come to think of it, might actually be kind of cool.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Things I Suck At</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/things-i-suck-at"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/things-i-suck-at</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;/categories/geek&#34;&gt;fiddle around with a lot of things.&lt;/a&gt;  It&amp;#8217;s in my nature. I began listing my recent forays into configuring email as an example, and I realized quite quickly that the odyssey ought to be its own post. The reason I do this sort of fiddling, though, almost always composed of two intertwining&amp;nbsp;mental&amp;nbsp;phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know what I&amp;nbsp;need,&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know the limitations of the thing I&amp;#8217;m&amp;nbsp;fiddling&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when we&amp;#8217;re talking about software or something similar, I know up front what the limitations are; often, though, I only find out by playing around with it. Likewise, I often know what I need up front; other times, though, I only find out what I need by finding out where my needs rub up against the limitations of whatever it is I&amp;#8217;m trying to&amp;nbsp;work&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w/71&#34;&gt;Back to Work 71&lt;/a&gt;, I started thinking about the problems that exist in organizations&amp;#8212;things like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://passiveaggressivenotes.com/&#34;&gt;passive aggression&lt;/a&gt; that Merlin and Dan were discussing&amp;#8212;as functions of that same pair of forces. More specifically, it made me think about the problems I have as a teacher with my students, the problems my students have with me as a teacher, and perhaps most importantly, the problems I have with myself as a teacher.  &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;All these problems&amp;#8212;and perhaps all problems&amp;#8212;come down to a conflict between one party&amp;#8217;s expectations and another&amp;nbsp;party&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;limitations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At that point&amp;#8212;and at that absurdly high level of abstraction&amp;#8212;there are two ways to go about resolving&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;problem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Revise the&amp;nbsp;expectation,&amp;nbsp;or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resolve&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;limitation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What occurred to me as I was listening is that in the same way that what David Allen calls the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wikisummaries.org/Getting_Things_Done:_The_Art_of_Stress-Free_Productivity#Chapter_9_--_Doing:_Making_the_Best_Action_Choices&#34;&gt;10,000 foot perspective&lt;/a&gt; is important to understanding the everyday projects and actions we undertake, &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;understanding my own limitations on a broad scale can, I think, help me avoid the problems I tend to face in the classroom (and, I&amp;nbsp;suspect,&amp;nbsp;beyond).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus: &lt;a href=&#34;/things-i-suck-at&#34;&gt;Things I Suck At&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remembering.&lt;/em&gt; Really: I don&amp;#8217;t remember &lt;em&gt;anything.&lt;/em&gt; If you talked to me about it half an hour ago, there&amp;#8217;s a decent chance I&amp;#8217;ve already forgotten it. I don&amp;#8217;t mean to; it&amp;#8217;s just the truth of me. If you need me to remember something, or to do something for you, &lt;em&gt;email me.&lt;/em&gt; Just talking to me will do pretty much&amp;nbsp;no&amp;nbsp;good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Planning ahead.&lt;/em&gt; I am writing this on July 11, 2012, and by my standards, that&amp;#8217;s an &lt;em&gt;absurd&lt;/em&gt; amount of foresight for a Fall semester. Whether with my classes or with my life, I am generally no good at planning ahead. Sometimes this is because I&amp;#8217;ve let time get away from me (see below), but a lot of the time&amp;#8212;at least in the context of my classes&amp;#8212;it&amp;#8217;s because what I&amp;#8217;m doing on any given day is determined by what&amp;#8217;s happened in class in the&amp;nbsp;days&amp;nbsp;before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The upshot for anyone more future-oriented than myself, though, is that if you ask me a question like &amp;#8220;What are we doing in class next Friday,&amp;#8221; I probably can&amp;#8217;t answer, because it likely depends rather a lot on what happens in class&amp;nbsp;next&amp;nbsp;Wednesday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estimating time.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MAN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; do I suck at this. I suck at this &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning my wife and I were talking about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ravelry.com/jobs&#34;&gt;a job posting&lt;/a&gt; that the reliably awesome folks at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ravelry.com/&#34;&gt;Ravelry&lt;/a&gt; have posted, and I said, &amp;#8220;I kinda want to apply&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;that.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;You can&amp;#8217;t,&amp;#8221; she said. &amp;#8220;It&amp;#8217;s a full time job.&amp;#8221; (I already have a full time job,&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;course.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t do it full time, sure, but maybe I could do it full time during the Summer, and half time during the&amp;nbsp;school&amp;nbsp;year.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Do you think you have twenty extra hours a week during&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;semester?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, until she said it like that, I did. I&amp;#8217;m just &lt;em&gt;awful&lt;/em&gt; both at judging how long things will take and at judging how much time I have to&amp;nbsp;do&amp;nbsp;the.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this reason, in class, I try never to say things like &amp;#8220;I will have X ready by Y,&amp;#8221; because one or both of those problems will likely make me wrong. I will usually say &amp;#8220;I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; have X by Y,&amp;#8221; which leaves me a little room to&amp;nbsp;be&amp;nbsp;wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tackling things piecemeal.&lt;/em&gt; Let&amp;#8217;s say today is Monday, and I have 50 student papers that were just turned in, and I want them to be back in student hands by Friday. What a normal person would do is try to tackle 10 papers a day, so that by the end of the day Friday, they&amp;#8217;re done.&amp;nbsp;Yay!&amp;nbsp;Reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will probably not do this. Instead, I will try to orchestrate things so that I have an enormous block of time so that I can do them all at once. This may or may not work, and because it&amp;#8217;s harder to get ten hours or so at a block than it is to get two hours together five times, it&amp;#8217;ll likely end up meaning that I don&amp;#8217;t accomplish things according to my&amp;nbsp;own&amp;nbsp;deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Prioritizing.&lt;/em&gt; Broadly speaking, I have no idea what is important and what is not. If I have five tasks I need to complete, I have a lot of trouble deciding which I should approach first, even if one of them is &amp;#8220;exit the burning building.&amp;#8221;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Being mean.&lt;/em&gt; This is a tough one. As a teacher, sometimes it&amp;#8217;s my job to be mean. I&amp;#8217;m good at that when it matters. If you need to fail my class, you need to fail my class&amp;#8212;and while that sucks for everybody, you&amp;#8217;re not going to be able to sweet-talk me out&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The times when I suck at being mean, though, are the little times. I set out my policies pretty clearly on my Syllabi, and I hold to those policies pretty clearly. So when someone comes to me and says, for example, &amp;#8220;I need to leave 45 minutes early today,&amp;#8221; I&amp;#8217;ll likely say &amp;#8220;Okay,&amp;#8221; and&amp;nbsp;mean&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, though, is that what the student hears is something like, &amp;#8220;Oh, of course visiting your out-of-state stylist for an elaborate purple up-do is more important than my class; by all means, come and go as you please and expect no consequences whatsoever.!&amp;#8221; When what I mean is &amp;#8220;Okay, that&amp;#8217;s your choice; as per the Syllabus, I&amp;#8217;ll be marking you&amp;nbsp;absent.&amp;nbsp;Ta!&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My intention is to both include this on my Syllabi next semester&amp;#8212;or at least, include a link to the relevant page&amp;#8212;and to use this list to help me design my courses, such that I can build my practices and policies &lt;em&gt;around&lt;/em&gt; my limitations, with the hope that I can thereby&amp;nbsp;avoid&amp;nbsp;problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll see how&amp;nbsp;it&amp;nbsp;goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both in terms of its role on my Syllabus and its role in my life, I recognize that this should probably be paired with a corresponding list of Things I&amp;#8217;m Pretty Good At, but at the moment, I&amp;#8217;m wanting to work on some of those limitations, so this is coming first.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Sublime Text 2 Markdown Footnote Goodness</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/sublime-text-2-markdown-footnote-goodness"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/sublime-text-2-markdown-footnote-goodness</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links&#34;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve converted the little python link gathering doodad I did into a command for &lt;a href=&#34;http://sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;. But, because I am an &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/sometimes-comics-are-essays-too&#34;&gt;aggressive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/feminism-marriage-proposals-comics&#34;&gt;footnoter&lt;/a&gt;, I decided I wanted some convenience functions for footnotes.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; And so I made&amp;nbsp;some.&amp;nbsp;Hooray.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jngeist/MarkdownEditing&#34;&gt;my fork of the MarkdownEditing Package&lt;/a&gt;. The furnished commands are&amp;nbsp;pretty&amp;nbsp;simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insert footnote.&lt;/em&gt; Press &lt;code&gt;^⌘6&lt;/code&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to insert a footnote after the current word.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gather missing footnotes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;⌘⌥⇧g&lt;/code&gt; will look for footnote markers that aren&amp;#8217;t currently defined and add markers at the bottom of your document. Not so useful by itself, I admit, but useful in conjunction with&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;next:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Switch to/from footnote definition.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;^⌥6&lt;/code&gt; will switch between the text of a footnote and its references. So: if my cursor is in a footnote, and I press &lt;code&gt;^⌥6&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ST2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; will select the references to the footnote in the body text. If my cursor is in a body paragraph, &lt;code&gt;^⌥6&lt;/code&gt;will identify the next footnote reference and take me to&amp;nbsp;its&amp;nbsp;text. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sort footnotes.&lt;/em&gt; If you saw this post initially, you saw that my footnotes were out of order. Inserting a new footnote &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; an existing footnote will result in the notes being added out of order, and at least in the flavor of Markdown I&amp;#8217;m using,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; this results in sorting oddities. (So: in the previous version of the post, the reference to footnote 4 came before footnote 1, and but footnote 1 came first in the &lt;code&gt;ol&lt;/code&gt; at the bottom of the page.) Now, &lt;code&gt;⌘^s&lt;/code&gt; will sort the footnotes in the order in which they appear in the document. This affects the sorting of the &lt;code&gt;ol&lt;/code&gt;, which in turn corrects the problem with&amp;nbsp;marker&amp;nbsp;ordering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Magic footnotes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;^6&lt;/code&gt; is a magic command that combines most of these commands. It does&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the current selection is in the text of a footnote, it moves the cursor to the&amp;nbsp;corresponding&amp;nbsp;reference(s).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the current selection is in a footnote reference, it moves the cursor to the corresponding&amp;nbsp;footnote&amp;nbsp;text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the current selection is neither (i.e., in the main text), it creates a&amp;nbsp;new&amp;nbsp;footnote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between these, this makes it really easy to go back and forth from footnotes to text. When I need to write a footnote, &lt;code&gt;^6&lt;/code&gt; will insert a new footnote, thusly.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Easy as&amp;nbsp;can&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously&amp;#8212;well, I think obviously&amp;#8212;&lt;a href=&#34;http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/&#34;&gt;core Markdown&lt;/a&gt; doesn&amp;#8217;t provide syntax for footnotes, and so this will only work with a flavor of Markdown that does.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 because &lt;code&gt;shift+6&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;^&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://fletcherpenney.net/multimarkdown/&#34;&gt;Multimarkdown&lt;/a&gt; syntax for a footnote.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works by scanning the current file for Multimarkdown footnote markers, identifying those that are numeric, and providing the next integer&amp;#8212;so you shouldn&amp;#8217;t have any marker collisions.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://freewisdom.org/projects/python-markdown/&#34;&gt;Python Markdown&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyde.github.com/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;, which, let&amp;#8217;s be frank&amp;#8212;who knows what madness lies within.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 4 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when I&amp;#8217;m done writing the footnote text, &lt;code&gt;^6&lt;/code&gt; will take me back to the top.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 5 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">A simple script for gathering missing Markdown links</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;As I was writing something else&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, I got distracted by a common problem and threw together a quick script to deal with it. It seems like I&amp;#8217;m pretty much the opposite of &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com&#34;&gt;Brett Terpstra&lt;/a&gt; when I write; his awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com/project/markdown-service-tools/&#34;&gt;Markdown Service Tools&lt;/a&gt; has a service to turn a group of tabs in Safari or Chrome to a list of Markdown reference links. But for me, it&amp;#8217;s a lot easier to write first and find links later, as a lot of the time I&amp;#8217;m not linking to research I&amp;#8217;m doing now but research I&amp;#8217;ve done in the past. So usually what I&amp;#8217;ll do when I want to link to something is simply include a link reference as I write (so, in the first link on this page, I&amp;#8217;ve just put &lt;code&gt;[Brett Terpstra][TERPstra]&lt;/code&gt;), and then promptly forget about them. When I finally get around to rendering the thing, I usually find a bunch of links I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten to&amp;nbsp;fill&amp;nbsp;in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I just threw&amp;nbsp;this&amp;nbsp;together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&#34;https://gist.github.com/3057158.js?file=gather_missing_md_links.py&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, it looks at a given file, identifies all the Markdown link references contained therein, and appends the reference marker at the end, waiting for the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. So, running it on this file, I&amp;#8217;ve got an eternally convenient &lt;code&gt;[TERPstra]:&lt;/code&gt; reminding me to enter the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; at the bottom. I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ll futz with this, and I&amp;#8217;ll update this post when I do. (Immediate to-do: set it up to accept input from &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;STDIN&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, so that I can use it as a filter in Sublime Text, and/or integrate it into my Markdown&amp;nbsp;build&amp;nbsp;system.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Update: July&amp;nbsp;8,&amp;nbsp;2012&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simpler way to do this occurred to me almost immediately: make this a &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.sublimetext.info/en/latest/extensibility/commands.html&#34;&gt;Sublime Text 2 Command&lt;/a&gt;. Since I&amp;#8217;m already using Terpstra&amp;#8217;s budding &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ttscoff/MarkdownEditing&#34;&gt;MarkdownEditing package&lt;/a&gt;, I just &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jngeist/MarkdownEditing.git&#34;&gt;forked&lt;/a&gt; his and added the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jngeist/MarkdownEditing/blob/master/gather_missing_links.py&#34;&gt;relevant command&lt;/a&gt;. Now, I can just hit &amp;#8997;&amp;#8984;G, and all my markers are collected&amp;nbsp;for&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I swear, it&amp;#8217;s an upcoming post about how easily distracted I am.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">On Endings</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/on-endings"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/on-endings</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Today, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://masseffect.wikia.com/wiki/Mass_Effect_3:_Extended_Cut&#34;&gt;Extended Cut&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 3&lt;/em&gt; has dropped. I haven&amp;#8217;t started it yet, but I&amp;#8217;m sure I will as soon as I post this. Before I get to the revision of the ending, though, I wanted to voice my thoughts about my experience of the&amp;nbsp;original&amp;nbsp;ending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I have, if obliquely, &lt;a href=&#34;http://killscreendaily.com/articles/essays/we-changed-ending/&#34;&gt;expressed my feelings regarding the reductiveness of the ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and at this point I feel like things are still &lt;em&gt;unfinished&lt;/em&gt; in that realm. While I don&amp;#8217;t yet feel ready to write much about &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I do want to write about &lt;em&gt;an&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;ending. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; series is full of fantastic writing, and particularly of moments wherein Shepard is (and therefore we are) forced to face decisions that are realistic in their complexity, if not their content. Even the game&amp;#8217;s paragon/renegade dichotomy speaks to this&amp;#8212;for one thing, there&amp;#8217;s nothing preventing a character from expressing both tendencies; for another, the tendencies align more with the &amp;#8220;lawful/chaotic&amp;#8221; spectrum&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; than the more traditional &amp;#8220;good/evil&amp;#8221; one. In particular, the tactical decision at the end of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; always stands out to me: sacrifice the council to minimize fleet losses, or let the fleet be culled to an unspecified amount at the expense of galactic leadership. There is no &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; answer (let alone a &amp;#8220;right&amp;#8221; one); instead, you have assess the risk to the fleet, assess the comparative value of this particular group of (kind of douchey) leaders, and decide which devastating loss is less devastating. It&amp;#8217;s that kind of tactical and moral sacrifice that is absent from the boxed ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;There is an ending to &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I think, that is beautiful and poignant and expertly written and that captures the moral and tactical quagmire that is the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; universe: the sequence after the mission on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9zMGTb0K-PI&amp;amp;t=8m0s&#34;&gt;Thessia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thessia itself, by and large, is a beautiful mission; throughout the mission, we are compelled again and again to confront the cost of Shepard&amp;#8217;s adventures. For the most part, Shepard gallivants about the galaxy at her own pace, solving problems, making peace, with the horrors on Earth transpiring invisibly at a fixed rate. We know of the losses, but we don&amp;#8217;t see them. On Thessia, we have to convince people to die for us, to hold the line in favor of a mission they don&amp;#8217;t even begin to understand. It is as if Earth is burning, and we ask, &amp;#8220;Will you sacrifice your friends&amp;#8217; lives so I can visit Westminster Abbey?&amp;#8221; And we ask again and again, and again and again these baffled asari give their lives because we are all there is left to&amp;nbsp;hope&amp;nbsp;for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then&amp;#8212;really, for the first time&amp;#8212;we fail. Shepard gets shamefully beat down by robo-&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Um8mMa5w41A&#34;&gt;Rufio&lt;/a&gt;, who takes her data and her certainty, leaving her utterly clueless about what she ought to be doing next. She fires, hopeless, at&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, in my mind, the true end of the &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;trilogy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following moments pepper Shepard&amp;#8217;s blank face like hail. The asari voice on the radio, calling for help and finding none, and then asking for that last, incomprehensible hope: &amp;#8220;Did anyone see what happened to Shepard? Did she get through?&amp;#8221; And the small, mortifying gratitude we feel that we cannot&amp;nbsp;answer&amp;nbsp;her. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blinking light of the vidcomm, which Shepard has answered so many times without hesitation, and which now, for the first time, she fears. The way she leans against the doorframe. The way her forehead rests on&amp;nbsp;her&amp;nbsp;arm. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The unconsidered assumption of the asari councilor. Her uncomprehending look when we tell her there&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;problem. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;dquo&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;We were…&amp;#8221; The hesitation as the unfamiliar word rolls up Shepard&amp;#8217;s throat from her gut, where it has festered, lingers a moment behind her eyes, and crawls retched from her&amp;nbsp;mouth:&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;defeated.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment of blind incomprehension on the councilor&amp;#8217;s face. The falling shock of reality. Her fumbling attempt to excuse herself to oversee the end of her civilization. There is nothing left to say. Shepard apologizes to an&amp;nbsp;empty&amp;nbsp;room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, the turn: Shepard&amp;#8217;s eternally recurrent decision to fight on, to look forward, to find the impossible&amp;nbsp;way&amp;nbsp;through. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have been happy, I think, if this was the end of gameplay. Our cycle fails, as did the cycles&amp;nbsp;before&amp;nbsp;us. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, after the credits, Buzz Aldrin still gets an inexplicable cameo as a species we&amp;#8217;ve never seen&amp;#8212;maybe one that looks just a little like a sapient pyjack, or varren&amp;#8212;finds a strange black box, and from it, we see Liara tell the story of Shepard. And perhaps we see just enough of this new cycle to believe that maybe this time, it is not&amp;nbsp;too&amp;nbsp;late. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, Traynor pipes cheerfully up with her &lt;em&gt;deus ex lesbos&lt;/em&gt; solution: &amp;#8220;by the way, I happen to know exactly where he went. It&amp;#8217;s a long shot except that it is &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;OBVIOUSLY&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;THE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ANSWER&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&amp;#8221; And so the game begins its&amp;nbsp;slow&amp;nbsp;descent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been said in these last weeks that the community&amp;#8217;s frustration about the ending arises from dissatisfaction at the lack of a &amp;#8220;happy&amp;#8221; ending, but I think that&amp;#8217;s a strawman. I certainly would&amp;#8217;ve preferred the possibility if an outcome in which something&amp;#8212;&lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8212;survived&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but the ending I describe isn&amp;#8217;t triumphant. It isn&amp;#8217;t &amp;#8220;victorious and uplifting.&amp;#8221; &lt;span class=&#34;pull&#34;&gt;But it is an ending earned, one which treats the characters, the world, the Reapers, and above all the players&amp;nbsp;with&amp;nbsp;respect.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I post this, I&amp;#8217;m going to start playing the Extended Cut, and I may or may not be satisfied. If I&amp;#8217;m not, I&amp;#8217;ll just call Thessia the end, and be satisfied.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you think about the world in terms of D&amp;amp;D. &amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DLC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#8220;The Arrival,&amp;#8221; it was revealed that destroying a Mass Relay would &lt;a href=&#34;http://masseffect.wikia.com/wiki/Arrival_(assignment)#Onboard_the_Shuttle&#34;&gt;destroy the system containing it&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More specifically, I&amp;#8217;ll make a Shepard that looks like Casey Hudson, such that the &amp;#8220;true&amp;#8221; ending to the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; series will be his apology to an empty room.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 3 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">"A Murderer's Work" out in *Creative Nonfiction*</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/a-murderers-work-out-in-creative-nonfiction"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/a-murderers-work-out-in-creative-nonfiction</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Exciting news! My essay &amp;#8220;A Murderer&amp;#8217;s Work&amp;#8221; has just been published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.creativenonfiction.org/cnfshop/product_info.php?cPath=24_26&amp;amp;products_id=323&#34;&gt;Issue 44&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.creativenonfiction.org/&#34;&gt;Creative Nonfiction&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s an honor to be published alongside the like of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bjhollars.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;B. J.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Hollars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://essays.quotidiana.org/&#34;&gt;Patrick Madden&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, if I do say so myself, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/Ar53M8kt&#34;&gt;typography&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;gorgeous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Events! Excitement! Exclamation Points!</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/events-excitement-exclamation-points"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/events-excitement-exclamation-points</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;As you can see, I&amp;#8217;ve shifted things around&amp;nbsp;a&amp;nbsp;bit. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been wanting to do this for some time, inasmuch as my old site&amp;#8212;lovely as it was, to be sure&amp;#8212;had a few key&amp;nbsp;limitations,&amp;nbsp;namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being&amp;nbsp;Wordpress&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being&amp;nbsp;exclusively&amp;nbsp;gamery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being&amp;nbsp;dated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being&amp;nbsp;boring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so. Because I am a &lt;a href=&#34;http://geekabouttown.com/categories/geek/&#34;&gt;geek&lt;/a&gt;, I have made things as complicated as I possibly can without having my wife kill me.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fully expect to spend a goodly bit of time tweaking this in the next few months/weeks/years/until the Internet ends, and I suspect I&amp;#8217;ll have more to say about the technologies I&amp;#8217;m using&amp;nbsp;as&amp;nbsp;well. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, the site is built on &lt;a href=&#34;http://hyde.github.com/&#34;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;, which is (as its name implies) &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s serially misunderstood, less-well-behaved alter-ego. There&amp;#8217;s plenty to love, and plenty to grumble about, but if you&amp;#8217;re choosing a static site generator, know this: the documentation for Hyde is a horsewreck.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; rel=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case,&amp;nbsp;hooray!&amp;nbsp;Website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, if I don&amp;#8217;t get this deployed tonight, I may have missed my window.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 1 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a trainwreck, but more out-of-date.&amp;#160;&lt;a class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; rev=&#34;footnote&#34; title=&#34;Jump back to footnote 2 in the text&#34;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Contrary to appearances&hellip;</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/contrary-to-appearances"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/contrary-to-appearances</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;So.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m&amp;nbsp;still&amp;nbsp;here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working on a redesign of this site for some long while now, and so I’ve been caught in the admittedly absurd mental trap wherein I don’t want to &lt;em&gt;write&lt;/em&gt; for my blog because I need to be working on the design. At this point, things are nearly (I hope) done, and so I’ll be resuming a more regular (or at least a more occasional)&amp;nbsp;publishing&amp;nbsp;calendar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unrelatedly, &lt;em&gt;Kill Screen&lt;/em&gt; is hosting some more of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://killscreendaily.com/articles/essays/we-changed-ending/&#34;&gt;oddjob handiwork&lt;/a&gt;. I thought it a fitting tribute to the end of the Mass Effect series. (For a minor easter egg, check out the id I gave the script element.&amp;nbsp;I’m&amp;nbsp;hilarious.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>