<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        Geek About Town - Excerpts    </title>
        <link href="/blog/excerpts.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2017-03-14T14:55:25Z</updated>

    <id>/blog/excerpts.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">On Microwaves and Human Dignity</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/on-microwaves-and-human-dignity"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/on-microwaves-and-human-dignity</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;Let me finally add that these calculations leave out the moral and emotional aspects of this process. Certainly, we can reduce microwaving to a question of mere efficiency, but this loses all of the complicated nuance of the task. How does one account for the feeling of pride one gets with a careful, accurate estimation? How does one factor in the way the food tastes just a little bit better knowing that its perfect temperature is the result of my own insight and forethought, rather than haphazard button-slapping? How too the knowledge that those who share the microwave with me will feel my respect and admiration manifested in a clean&amp;nbsp;timer?&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">The Phenomenology of Purpose</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/the-phenomenology-of-purpose"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/the-phenomenology-of-purpose</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you negotiate &amp;#8230; the conflicts/tensions between student purposes in their writing and the purposes we assume they have to learn about in academic&amp;nbsp;writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to interrogate your slash. Does it stand for &amp;#8220;or?&amp;#8221; Does it stand for &lt;em&gt;beziehungsweise?&lt;/em&gt; Does it clarify? Tension is not always conflict. Think &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tensegrity&#34;&gt;tensegrity&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;http://static.panoramio.com/photos/large/62016957.jpg&#34;&gt;impossible things&lt;/a&gt; stand tall because their tension balances them. Tension is sometimes harmony, or at least tension can sometimes be&amp;nbsp;harmonized.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">A Collection of Oddities</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/a-collection-of-oddities"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/a-collection-of-oddities</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From time to time I get emails or twitter mentions from other people who also thought some of my web experiments at &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://killscreen.com/author/j-nicholas-geist/&#34;&gt;Kill Screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; were neat, and wondering where they are. So (with &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;KS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8216;s permission) I&amp;#8217;m republishing &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/&#34;&gt;some of those oddities here&lt;/a&gt;. The first of them is one of my favorite things I&amp;#8217;ve ever written, my review of &lt;a href=&#34;/oddities/infinity-blade/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Infinity Blade&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;m glad it&amp;#8217;s back up&amp;nbsp;somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Audiobooks and the Platonic Story</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/audiobooks-and-the-platonic-story</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;I was listening to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maximumfun.org/bullseye/judge-john-hodgman-episode-151-sic-semper-dramatis&#34;&gt;not-very-recent episode of &lt;em&gt;Judge John Hodgman&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; recently where Judge Hodgman, Bailiff Jesse, and an unspeakably fabulous man debated the equivalence of reading and listening to audiobooks, and ever since I&amp;#8217;ve been paying much more attention to the different dynamics of the experiences. Having just made it through Spring Break, and as a regular commuter, I&amp;#8217;ve been doing a lot of both, and my feeling&amp;#8212;somewhat surprisingly&amp;#8212;is that Judge Hodgman was right: they are &amp;#8220;separate but equal&amp;#8221; experiences. A book and its audiobook offer two fundamentally different ways to experience the story they&amp;nbsp;describe.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Better sorting with Keyboard Maestro Macro Palettes</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/better-sorting-with-keyboard-maestro-macro-palettes</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;As a teacher, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://inthecourseofmyduties.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;comment&lt;/a&gt; on a &lt;em&gt;lot&lt;/em&gt; of student writing. I usually do this digitally, as my handwriting is so awful as to make doctors weep. And, because students in the same classes tend to be learning the same things at the same time, I often find myself needing to say the same thing over and over, to lots of students in lots of different&amp;nbsp;classes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I need to be able to inject these comments quickly, easily, and repeatedly, I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to find a good way to automate them for some time now. In my last attempt, I&amp;#8217;ve figured out a pretty good way to do this—solving a long-standing problem I&amp;#8217;ve had with Keyboard Maestro in the&amp;nbsp;process.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">*Assassin's Creed's* Identity Crisis</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/assassins-creeds-identity-crisis</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;Iteration is important. One of the most elegant things about the difference between, say, &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect 2&lt;/em&gt; is the way in which the combat system builds on what has come before. On the one hand, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; feels like &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; On the other, it&amp;#8217;s streamlined. Simpler. More elegant. And what speaks most highly for it, I think, is that I feel like playing &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; made me better understand what combat in &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; was &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to&amp;nbsp;be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I recognize that games that come in series are &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to iterate. But having just finished &lt;em&gt;Assassin&amp;#8217;s Creed: Revelations,&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;#8217;m starting to remember the &lt;em&gt;dangers&lt;/em&gt; of&amp;nbsp;iteration.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Things I Suck At</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/things-i-suck-at"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/things-i-suck-at</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;/categories/geek&#34;&gt;fiddle around with a lot of things.&lt;/a&gt;  It&amp;#8217;s in my nature. I began listing my recent forays into configuring email as an example, and I realized quite quickly that the odyssey ought to be its own post. The reason I do this sort of fiddling, though, almost always composed of two intertwining mental&amp;nbsp;phenomena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know what I need,&amp;nbsp;and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I know the limitations of the thing I&amp;#8217;m fiddling&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, when we&amp;#8217;re talking about software or something similar, I know up front what the limitations are; often, though, I only find out by playing around with it. Likewise, I often know what I need up front; other times, though, I only find out what I need by finding out where my needs rub up against the limitations of whatever it is I&amp;#8217;m trying to work&amp;nbsp;with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I was listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://5by5.tv/b2w/71&#34;&gt;Back to Work 71&lt;/a&gt;, I started thinking about the problems that exist in organizations&amp;#8212;things like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://passiveaggressivenotes.com/&#34;&gt;passive aggression&lt;/a&gt; that Merlin and Dan were discussing&amp;#8212;as functions of that same pair of forces. More specifically, it made me think about the problems I have as a teacher with my students, the problems my students have with me as a teacher, and perhaps most importantly, the problems I have with myself as a teacher.  ((All these problems&amp;#8212;and perhaps all problems&amp;#8212;come down to a conflict between one party&amp;#8217;s expectations and another party&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;limitations.))&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Sublime Text 2 Markdown Footnote Goodness</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/sublime-text-2-markdown-footnote-goodness"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/sublime-text-2-markdown-footnote-goodness</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;As I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links&#34;&gt;previously&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve converted the little python link gathering doodad I did into a command for &lt;a href=&#34;http://sublimetext.com&#34;&gt;Sublime Text 2&lt;/a&gt;. But, because I am an &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/sometimes-comics-are-essays-too&#34;&gt;aggressive&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;/posts/feminism-marriage-proposals-comics&#34;&gt;footnoter&lt;/a&gt;, I decided I wanted some convenience functions for footnotes.[^4] And so I made some.&amp;nbsp;Hooray.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">A simple script for gathering missing Markdown links</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/a-simple-script-for-gathering-missing-markdown-links</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;As I was writing something else[^1], I got distracted by a common problem and threw together a quick script to deal with it. It seems like I&amp;#8217;m pretty much the opposite of &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com&#34;&gt;Brett Terpstra&lt;/a&gt; when I write; his awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://brettterpstra.com/project/markdown-service-tools/&#34;&gt;Markdown Service Tools&lt;/a&gt; has a service to turn a group of tabs in Safari or Chrome to a list of Markdown reference links. But for me, it&amp;#8217;s a lot easier to write first and find links later, as a lot of the time I&amp;#8217;m not linking to research I&amp;#8217;m doing now but research I&amp;#8217;ve done in the past. So usually what I&amp;#8217;ll do when I want to link to something is simply include a link reference as I write (so, in the first link on this page, I&amp;#8217;ve just put &lt;code&gt;[Brett Terpstra][TERPstra]&lt;/code&gt;), and then promptly forget about them. When I finally get around to rendering the thing, I usually find a bunch of links I&amp;#8217;ve forgotten to fill&amp;nbsp;in.&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">On Endings</title>
            <author><name>J. Nicholas Geist</name></author>
            <link href="/posts/on-endings"/>
            <updated>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-12-14T00:00:00Z</published>
            <id>/posts/on-endings</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                
                &lt;p&gt;I think I have, if obliquely, &lt;a href=&#34;http://killscreendaily.com/articles/essays/we-changed-ending/&#34;&gt;expressed my feelings regarding the reductiveness of the ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and at this point I feel like things are still &lt;em&gt;unfinished&lt;/em&gt; in that realm. While I don&amp;#8217;t yet feel ready to write much about &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I do want to write about &lt;em&gt;an&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;ending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Mass Effect&lt;/em&gt; series is full of fantastic writing, and particularly of moments wherein Shepard is (and therefore we are) forced to face decisions that are realistic in their complexity, if not their content. Even the game&amp;#8217;s paragon/renegade dichotomy speaks to this&amp;#8212;for one thing, there&amp;#8217;s nothing preventing a character from expressing both tendencies; for another, the tendencies align more with the &amp;#8220;lawful/chaotic&amp;#8221; spectrum[^1] than the more traditional &amp;#8220;good/evil&amp;#8221; one. In particular, the tactical decision at the end of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; always stands out to me: sacrifice the council to minimize fleet losses, or let the fleet be culled to an unspecified amount at the expense of galactic leadership. There is no &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; answer (let alone a &amp;#8220;right&amp;#8221; one); instead, you have assess the risk to the fleet, assess the comparative value of this particular group of (kind of douchey) leaders, and decide which devastating loss is less devastating. It&amp;#8217;s that kind of tactical and moral sacrifice that is absent from the boxed ending of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;((There is an ending to &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I think, that is beautiful and poignant and expertly written and that captures the moral and tactical quagmire that is the &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;ME&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; universe: the sequence after the mission on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9zMGTb0K-PI&amp;amp;t=8m0s&#34;&gt;Thessia&lt;/a&gt;.))&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>